DM: I guess
Unknown: Yes
Seeker: Um, I finally found my, my beard.
DM: Awesome. [laughs]
Seeker: [laughs]
DM: Okay. So,
DM: after, um, setting out from
DM: the town of Karawa on the trail of these giant hyenas,
DM: getting slightly lost in the canyon lands and rocky desert, finding your way to the road,
DM: talking to a,
DM: uh, a scout who had been, um, riding from the Gomat Oasis earlier that morning, you pressed on through the heat of the desert
DM: sun
DM: into the early evening.
DM: Sun sets, and you arrived
DM: exhausted, most of you exhausted,
DM: tired from your long day, at the Gomat Oasis.
DM: In the distance as you approach the, the, um-
Seeker: [laughs]
DM: ... off the, the trade road heading towards the sort of p- the open water of the oasis and the, um,
DM: little cluster of trees and tents and a few small stone buildings
DM: that, uh, that mark this way station on the far eastern frontier of Dunmar, you see in front of you,
DM: not having noticed you yet, three enormous lizards, maybe 10 feet long, ripping into, uh, the dead
DM: b- bloodied bodies of sheep scattered around-
Seeker: [laughs]
DM: ... the tents. There's no other signs of life.
DM: The, uh, couple of tents are flapping in the wind.
DM: There's no fire lit, only the moonlight, um, in the, in the twilight, uh, as you approach.
DM: What would you like to do?
Kenzo: And are you mean- uh, um,
Kenzo: like the lizards have like killed all, all life in the oasis, or just this one area?
DM: Uh, they've k- they've killed...
DM: Uh, well, you can't see...
DM: There's like a, there's like a pool, and you can only see the close end of the pool.
DM: The far end of the pool is, is sort of hidden in darkness.
DM: The, the oasis itself is like an open area of water that's maybe, uh,
DM: 60, 70 feet across, and surrounded by, by some short trees and scrubs, so you can't see all the way across.
DM: There's a collection of three tents set up here, nothing moving in the tents, and the only apparent life is the three giant lizards, and there's
DM: a herd of sheep that has been decimated by them, and the sheep themselves are lying dead and being chewed on by these beasts.
Kenzo: Is there any sign of life in the tents?
DM: Uh-
Unknown: Inside chance?
DM: Make a perception check.
Wellby: I'll do the same. And can we also look, are there any like human body parts on the ground, or is it just, uh-
DM: Uh, I can say that's part of the same perception check.
DM: Um...
Seeker: Um-
Wellby: [laughs]
Seeker: Can I, um...
Seeker: I'm, I'm interested i- if there's any traces of, of magic around, if these are magical creatures or not, if there's any source of their power or-
DM: Uh-
Delwath: They like noticed us, or are they like contending-
DM: They haven't noticed you right now.
DM: You're... Actually, you're probably a little bit further away.
DM: Let's say you're about 70 feet away, back here.
DM: Um, and they are pretty intent on the, on their meal.
DM: They're sort of ripping into the carcasses of these, of these sheep.
DM: Um,
DM: let's see. Uh,
DM: so Seeker and Kenzo, you, um, notice...
DM: There doesn't... The, the tents themselves seem to be sort of, uh, ripped to pieces, and there's not...
DM: You don't hear anything other than the sort of flapping of, of the sort of fabric and hide that makes up-
Unknown: Okay
DM: ... um, the tents. You don't notice any,
DM: uh... You can see, um, let's see, seven dead bodies of sheep, but you don't notice any other dead creatures, uh, at least in the immediate vicinity
DM: of these, of these lizards.
Kenzo: I, uh, lean over to you all and just whisper, um,
Kenzo: "I don't see any humans, just, just the dead sheep."
Seeker: Hmm.
Seeker: Maybe we should keep our distance [laughs] from those things.
Seeker: I wonder if they're like the hyenas or not.
Seeker: Uh, somebody have, knows if, if, if, uh,
Seeker: these are, uh... Anybody know if they're kind of, uh, endemic wildlife?
Seeker: Like, you know, local-
Unknown: Yeah, I mean, are these-
Seeker: [laughs] Local
Delwath: ... any ideas of can we tell if they're like, um-
Seeker: Local creatures?
Unknown: ... creatures or-
Seeker: Maybe they're the inhabitants of this oasis
Unknown: ... yeah.
DM: Maybe they l- you know.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: And, um, let's see. I guess, um-
Unknown: Nature?
DM: Wellby is probably the only one who's really spent much time, um...
DM: But yeah, you can make, make a nature check.
DM: I would say Wellby plus anybody who's proficient, but you're, you're exhausted, so you have disadvantage.
DM: I forgot about that.
Unknown: Oh, Wellby got 21, though.
Seeker: Well, Delweth got 22.
DM: Oh, snap.
DM: But you have to roll, uh, well, you're not exhausted.
Delwath: I'm not exhausted. I made my save.
DM: Right. Um,
DM: so
DM: you're also exhausted, Seeker.
DM: You gotta roll twice and take the, take the lower.
Seeker: Harsh.
DM: Um, so Delweth, you, um,
DM: uh, you, you wouldn't say they're common creatures, but, um, you know, definitely there's...
DM: In your, I mean, your experience is not particularly up to date, uh, for the, you know, this-
Wellby: Right
DM: ... this territory, but y- you know, you would have heard some, some stories just from being in Karawa for the past...
DM: ... three months, right?
DM: People talk about these sorts of creatures, like, you know, you would have seen, you probably would have seen, uh, you know, like somebody might have had a, a tooth of a giant lizard or,
DM: or, or something like that.
DM: So they're not, um,
DM: they're not unheard of.
DM: They're certainly not-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... common,
DM: uh,
DM: sort of in, in this,
DM: this close to Gomat, sort of the eastern edge of, of Dunmar.
DM: Nobody really takes their herds east of Gomat-
Unknown: But-
DM: ... and they're, but they're not, like s-
Unknown: Uh, unlike-
DM: ... unusual magical creatures
Delwath: ... like the giant hyenas were, were basically never heard of kinds of things, right?
DM: Um, yes.
Unknown: And these are unlike those.
Delwath: These are things that, like, they are probably wild beasts.
DM: Yes.
Unknown: So could we scare them off?
Seeker: Hmm.
DM: Sure. You could try.
Seeker: But what's scary-
DM: If they're-
Seeker: ... to a li- a giant lizard?
Kenzo: Are they, uh... Is Kenzo scared of them?
Kenzo: Like, could I... Do I feel like I could fight them?
Kenzo: Like, do they look scary, or do they look like, like would I wanna, m- you know?
Unknown: Do I, like I, do I think I could fight them?
DM: Uh, th- I mean, they're not nothing, but they, the- you wouldn't...
DM: Y- your sense is they're probably not as, uh, as brutal as the giant hyenas.
Unknown: I see. Okay. Okay.
DM: Okay.
Seeker: Hmm.
Unknown: What should we do?
Seeker: I, I'm still wondering if they're magical in origin or not.
Seeker: We have no evidence that they are.
Unknown: I mean, we could-
Seeker: Do I have any way, aside from detec- casting detect magic, of finding that out?
DM: No. Uh, you could-
Seeker: Ooh, ritual
DM: ... so detect magic is a ritual, so you could cast this.
Seeker: Let me, let me do that.
DM: So that takes 10 minutes but doesn't use a spell slot.
Seeker: But we're just, like hanging out. Like, are we hidden a little bit, like, behind a
Seeker: mesa or something?
DM: You're, you're not exactly hidden, but you're not particularly close to them.
Seeker: We should try to make sure they don't notice us, you guys.
Seeker: [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: That might be reasonable.
Seeker: Um,
Seeker: yeah, so I'm gonna try this ritual to
Seeker: see if I can sense any magic coming off of them,
Seeker: but it'll take a few minutes.
Unknown: Wait.
Wellby: Do we, do we...
Wellby: I mean, i- is it, is it real- i- is it reasonable to do a 10-minute ritual, like, 75 feet away from them, though?
Seeker: Oh.
DM: The range of detect magic is only 30 feet, so if you wanna sense if they're magic, you're gonna have to get closer.
Seeker: Good.
Unknown: What's the-
DM: Come-
Unknown: ... terrain between us and them?
Delwath: Is this just open ground?
DM: It's, it's open ground, yeah.
DM: It's sort of rocky desert, but it's not...
DM: It's basically just open ground.
DM: A few little bits of scrub, but no tall plants.
DM: The only tall plants are around the oasis.
DM: So right now you're sort of, you know, froze when you caught sight of them sort of at the edge of, of the, you know, in the dimness.
DM: Um,
DM: and you've been still and talking quietly, and they haven't seemed to notice, but you're not hidden in any way.
DM: If one of them happens to finish its sheep and look up, it will probably see you.
Unknown: Let's, let's hide.
Delwath: I think we should s- s- I think we should see if we can sneak around to behind these trees up here.
Seeker: Oh, I'm not seeing that.
Delwath: If you go all the way up to the top of the map.
Seeker: Oh, thank you. Yeah, let's, let's take some cover.
Unknown: Good idea.
Delwath: Right. Like, we could... And that's also,
Delwath: that's pretty close to...
Delwath: It's maybe not quite 30 feet, but it's pretty close.
Seeker: I'm also wondering if a very, very loud sound would scare them off.
Delwath: That's what I was wondering, too, but it seems like, it seems like if we walked kind of along the far edge...
Unknown: Oops. I just lost it.
Unknown: There we go.
DM: If you wanted to hide and be within 30 feet, if you head, you hid behi- you know, sort of in the back of this
DM: hide tent here, that would be within 30 feet of, of this one.
Seeker: All right. Let's do it.
Wellby: I think, though, uh, on the other hand.
Seeker: [laughs] Yeah, Schwartz.
Wellby: Three of us are exhausted.
Wellby: We have the element of surprise right now.
Unknown: Should we just-
Wellby: I think it's unlikely we can get all the way over there and hide successfully without them noticing.
Wellby: I think we, we should either fall back, which is probably the wise, prudent course to take, or we should just use the moment-
Unknown: Drive.
Seeker: Yeah.
Wellby: Or we should what?
Seeker: What is the time of day again?
Wellby: Attack.
DM: It's night. Early night.
DM: It's, like, n- nine o'clock.
DM: The sun has just, has set about an hour ago, so it's the end of twilight.
Kenzo: How does just, how does exhaustion impact our fighting abilities?
DM: Doesn't impact your fighting abilities.
DM: It just means you have disadvantage on, on ability checks, so skill rolls until you sleep.
Wellby: Oh, but not attack rolls.
DM: Not attack rolls.
Seeker: I, [laughs] I see a plan forming there, Wellby.
Seeker: [laughs] Is it an advisable one?
Seeker: [laughs]
Unknown: I mean,
Delwath: I think if we get them by surprise, Dr- I mean, okay, Tim, with my Nature, I mean, how, how dangerous are these things likely to be?
DM: So-
Delwath: Is the rumor that they kill, you know, a, a party of 20 went after them and two survived, or is it, like, one lone hunter takes them out?
DM: Uh,
DM: no. A lone hunter wouldn't, wouldn't a- attempt to take out a, a group of them by themselves.
DM: They are, like, you know, they're typically not encountered in packs.
DM: So, like, a group of, of herders and scouts might try and scare off one who was, who was menacing their sheep.
DM: Um, a sort of just, like, normal commoner would probably be
DM: nervous about a pack of them.
DM: Um-
Delwath: Sure
DM: ... but, but from, you know, they seem,
DM: they don't seem as, as
DM: scary or dangerous as, as the hyenas, right?
DM: The giant hyenas were definitely in another class th- than these.
Delwath: I think we should just attack them and-
Wellby: I think we should.
Wellby: We have surprise, let's do it.
Seeker: So I'll sneak around behind them,
Seeker: use my giant booming thunder wave sound to flush them out towards the rest of you.
Delwath: I, I-
Seeker: And then... [laughs]
Delwath: Well, sure. I just think by the time you get around, unless you're particularly talented at hiding...
Wellby: We-
Seeker: Uh-
Wellby: Do we all have ranged weapons?
Wellby: I ask as I unshoulder my bow and notch, nock in the arrow.
Seeker: I mean, I have this crossbow.
Seeker: I'm not brilliant with it, though.
Kenzo: Um, that, use that, use that weapon and, or, or use that weapon, Halfling.
Kenzo: Bring them close and we'll...
Delwath: Um, Delwath just kind of, um, he, he sort of, he, he nod.
Delwath: He just holds up an empty hand and says, "Yes."
Wellby: 'Cause, 'cause there's nothing in your hand.
Seeker: [laughs] I've seen that guy shoot some sparks, though.
DM: Okay. So
DM: here we go. Um,
DM: you, your first,
DM: uh, the f-
Delwath: Are we-
DM: You will get a surprise round, so you can all act.
DM: Their turns get skipped on the first round.
DM: So Kenzo, you're up first.
Delwath: Wait, did everybody roll initiative?
DM: Uh, oh, no. It rolled for you.
DM: Roll initiative and I'll replace your rolls.
Delwath: How did it roll for us?
DM: I have a, an, a API that, um...
DM: But it can't roll for you, 'cause it doesn't have your dex in the-
Delwath: Ah, okay
DM: ... program. It just-
Delwath: Well, I rolled a 14
DM: ... it just rolls a D20.
Delwath: Yeah.
DM: Um,
DM: Seeker is a six.
DM: Wellby
DM: is a nine. Where is Wellby?
DM: Wellby.
DM: Nine. S- I still have you as all, a roll 20.
DM: I'll fix that.
DM: Uh, Kenzo is a five.
Wellby: So Matthew makes this mini-fig last night.
Wellby: I describe, like, "Here's who the character is, what he looks like," and goes-
Seeker: Yeah, with his-
Wellby: ... pouring through to find all the parts, and he says, "Well, what's his name?"
Wellby: I say, "Wellby Goodbarrel."
Wellby: He says, "That, that is the worst name I have ever heard."
Seeker: [laughs]
DM: [laughs] Harsh.
DM: Harsh.
Delwath: Harsh. Very harsh.
Wellby: The only good part is the Goodbarrel.
DM: Ha.
Seeker: I mean, that part's good.
DM: Yeah, this is bothering me, so let me just see if I can fix your name.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: Nobody shows up with names in my version of the turn tracker.
Seeker: Yeah, I don't have any. Maybe you can, if you-
Delwath: I only have my own name.
Seeker: Oh, no?
DM: I don't know why that is.
Wellby: Yeah, I have my name.
Delwath: I think there's probably some setting where they're like-
DM: There's probably a setting where it's a, it's just a GM-
Delwath: Oh, because Tim, they're not PCs.
Delwath: They don't show up as PCs.
DM: Ah, right.
Seeker: Mm.
Delwath: I'm the only PC on my view.
DM: Okay, Delwath, you're first.
Delwath: All right. Um,
Delwath: I will,
Delwath: uh, let's see.
Kenzo: They're, they're, like, less than, yeah, they're...
Kenzo: Wait, can you, can I measure?
Delwath: They're less than 90 feet away, right?
DM: Um, yes.
DM: From you, one,
DM: two...
DM: Yeah, they're fif- the closest one is 50 feet.
Delwath: All right. Um-
DM: And the, the back one is about 60 feet, 60, 70 feet.
Delwath: So I'm gonna move a little bit just to be sort of a little bit in the front.
Delwath: Um, and then I will, um, mutter a incantation, like a, a incantation under my breath, um, cast, and then
Delwath: blast, send a blast up.
Delwath: So I'm casting
Delwath: Hex.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: And I'll just blast.
DM: On which one?
Delwath: Uh, the front one.
DM: This one here? Okay.
Delwath: Yeah.
Delwath: So-
DM: Um,
DM: that hits.
Delwath: And then, so then the, they would also do that roll.
Delwath: One hex damage.
Seeker: What, what do we see?
Delwath: Uh, you see a blast of force.
Delwath: Um, the, the, the hex, you don't see anything, and then you see a beam of crackling energy fly from Delwath's hand and smack the lizard.
DM: So as that smacks the lizards, the, they, it, like, roars in pain and sort of looks up from its sheep.
DM: And as it's roaring, the other two turn around, and you've clearly been spotted at this point.
DM: But you still have the element of surprise, so they don't get to act.
DM: Wellby.
Wellby: All right. I will, uh, shoot an arrow.
DM: That misses.
Wellby: Oh.
Seeker: Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
DM: As your arrow-
Wellby: With, with advantage, right?
Wellby: No, it is not with adv- just surprise.
DM: You're not hidden, you're just...
DM: They can see you, so you don't get advantage.
Wellby: Got it.
DM: Uh, okay. That guy doesn't get to go.
DM: Seeker of Highkeep.
Seeker: Um, I, uh, uh,
Seeker: hold my hands up in the air in front of me.
Seeker: My fingertips begin to glow, and I draw a complex weaving star-shaped symbol that hovers in the air between my hands.
Seeker: And with, uh, three quick gestures,
Seeker: I flick it towards each of my fellow party members, and it flies over and, um, sticks to your forehead,
Seeker: uh, and you feel bardic inspired.
DM: So you gotta pick one per- one of them.
DM: You can't do all three.
Seeker: What? Oh, I can't do all three?
Seeker: Damn.
DM: So it's a bonus action, so you have to do, you do one as a bonus action.
Delwath: Oh.
Delwath: Um,
Delwath: uh,
Delwath: Kenzo.
DM: Okay. So Kenzo, any time you roll a D20, if you don't like the roll, you can roll a D6 and add it to the roll.
Kenzo: Sweet. And so over at, um,
Kenzo: at the Seeker of Highkeep and nod.
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: which part?
Seeker: Uh, it's still my turn.
DM: Yeah, it's still your turn. That's just your bonus.
DM: You still have an action.
Delwath: Um,
Delwath: I, uh...
Delwath: Hmm.
Seeker: I will, uh, fire off a, uh, crossbow shot.
Delwath: Where's that?
Seeker: Uh, how do I do it?
DM: Go to, um-
Delwath: Oh, there we go.
DM: That misses, unfortunately.
Seeker: I still have a perfect record with my crossbow.
Delwath: [laughs]
DM: Okay, Kenzo, you're up.
Kenzo: Yikes. Um, I'm gonna range back then.
Unknown: How, how, how many, how many...
Kenzo: How far can I move, uh?
DM: Uh, you can move, uh, six, six squares.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: Well, you could... You take two move, I mean, if you want to, you could.
DM: You can, you can use your action to move 12 squares.
DM: So you can move six squares without doing anything.
DM: If you use your action to dash, you can move another six squares.
Seeker: Um, I am going to...
Unknown: What shall I do? Um-
Delwath: Can you turn up the music just a tiny bit, Tim?
DM: Yep.
Kenzo: I think I'm gonna go, um, I'm gonna head, like, north a little bit and try to draw, oh, draw the, uh,
Kenzo: uh... I want to fight one of them, not, like, three of them.
Kenzo: I don't wanna, like, run all the way up into them.
Unknown: Um,
Kenzo: like, what... Oh, so bardic inspiration, huh?
Kenzo: Yeah. There... Are, are diagonal tiles considered one tile?
DM: Yep.
Unknown: One, two, three, four.
Kenzo: I could get up to the...
Kenzo: Yeah, but if I run all the way up to them, then they'll all attack me, so.
Delwath: Yeah. We shouldn't...
Delwath: You shouldn't, you know, just go charging into battle all by yourself.
Kenzo: I think maybe what I'll do is I'm just gonna move, like, kind of over here.
DM: Yeah. Yeah.
Kenzo: And, um, just so when they come, um, I can, I can, uh, I can pinch off the first one.
Unknown: I can try to, you know-
Delwath: You can, you can ready an action to attack whenever somebody comes near you.
Delwath: [laughs]
Kenzo: I'll do that. So is this a good spot, guys?
Kenzo: Or should I get a little closer? What do you think?
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: I think that's good.
Delwath: That's a good spot.
Kenzo: All right. So Tim, I'll stay here and I'll ready an action.
Kenzo: I'll, I'll, I'll get my... I've got my quarter staff and I'm ready to, ready to fuck with the guy.
Wellby: That'll be too... If they're slow, we can keep hitting them as they're coming towards us.
Unknown: Exactly.
Delwath: Yes.
DM: Okay. So, uh,
DM: the, a couple of, um, arrows have sort of flown and landed abom- around them, but the main, uh, thing that any of these things have seen is those cackling
DM: blast of force, and they just, like, all look at Delwath and just roar.
DM: And hold on, I gotta see.
Unknown: Uh-
DM: This guy's gonna move.
DM: One, one, two-
Seeker: They're probably pretty slow. They can't really get to us that quickly, I'm sure
DM: ... four, five, six, seven, eight.
Seeker: Lumbering lizard gate, not
Seeker: like 60 mile an hour scrabbling.
DM: They're just gonna start dashing towards you.
Seeker: Oh, God. Oh, God.
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: Like-
Delwath: That's okay
DM: ... sort of rearing up on its hind limbs.
DM: Um, and that's gonna bring us to Delwath again.
Delwath: All right. There's nothing that succeeds like success.
Delwath: So I'm going to...
Delwath: Let's see, um-
DM: Interesting, interesting
Delwath: ... I'm gonna ta- let's see.
Delwath: Ha- hmm. I'm gonna take a few steps out.
Delwath: Well,
Delwath: I'll stand there, and then I'll do the exact same thing against the guy who I hit last time.
DM: Okay.
DM: That hits again.
Delwath: Mm-hmm.
DM: So do your, yep, hex.
DM: Okay. So as this, a second blast of force smashes into this lizard, it sort of, it staggers back and looks pretty badly wounded at this point.
DM: It sort of-
Delwath: And I'll, I'll draw my sword, too, just in case
DM: ... bellowing in pain.
Kenzo: The lead one? The one that's in front?
DM: This one right here.
Delwath: Yeah.
Wellby: The middle one.
DM: The middle one.
Unknown: All right.
DM: Okay. This one is also gonna go one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, 10.
Seeker: Oh, God. Oh, oh, man.
DM: 10.
Delwath: Th- oh, geez.
Wellby: [laughs]
Delwath: We could probably-
DM: 12, it can get to about there
Seeker: ... we could easily outrun these guys, I'm sure.
DM: Wellby.
Wellby: Uh, I'm gonna move
Wellby: lightly to spread out.
Wellby: Um, can I still get line of sight on the wounded one in back, even if there's another one in front of it?
DM: Um,
DM: yeah, there's a, there's a path through there.
Wellby: All right. So I'm gonna move, like, one, two, three, four,
Wellby: hmm, five. Something like that.
DM: Okay.
Wellby: And, um, I'm gonna try and hit the wounded one again with an arrow.
Wellby: So last time, I snapped off the shot too quick.
Wellby: This time, I scramble backwards to put a little bit of distance, crouch down on one knee, sight carefully, and-
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: There we go.
DM: That hits.
Delwath: Hey, hey.
Wellby: [clears throat]
DM: So as your arrow... But you don't get sneak attack.
Wellby: Uh, it just puts it in automatically, I think.
DM: Oh, okay.
Delwath: It does put it in automatically.
DM: Right. So as your arrow hits-
Delwath: That happened when I was playing around
DM: ... it st- it s- steps back again, and, like, there's blood coming down, and it looks upward, at you, and it just roars again and just runs forward,
DM: like, blood dripping.
Kenzo: Which one was the bloody one?
DM: This one that's moving now, not seeming to care.
DM: Ah. Oops, sorry.
DM: That wasn't supposed to happen.
DM: And it runs up to you and just, like, l- leans up and roars in front of the thing that hit it last, um, blood oozing out.
DM: It looks like it's, it's barely alive, um, but now it's roaring in front of you.
DM: Okay, Seeker.
Seeker: Um, okay.
Seeker: So the th- the thunder wave geometry is a 15-foot cube.
Seeker: Um-
DM: If you could, if you went right there-
Seeker: I could hit all three of them?
DM: You could hit all three of them and nobody else.
Seeker: Uh, is that, is that a good idea?
Seeker: 'Cause I could like-
Wellby: Would that affect him?
DM: No, it doesn't affect him
Seeker: ... it, it, it, it emits from me, it sort of shoots out
Seeker: around me. Can I get there?
Seeker: I guess I have 25.
Seeker: Yeah, so I could.
DM: Yeah, the only thing is this wounded one would get an attack of opportunity on you.
Seeker: I think I don't want that to happen.
Delwath: Wait, can't you sneak by?
Delwath: One-
DM: Oh, no, yes, you can
Delwath: ... two, three
DM: Yeah, you-
Delwath: Three
DM: ... no, 'cause then you'd go with-
Delwath: Four, five.
Delwath: You'd never be within f- oh, right that square you would
DM: ... yes, it's in five feet of it.
Delwath: Hmm.
DM: You can't really fit between it and Delwath without it getting an attack of opportunity on you.
Seeker: But could I go, like, over here kind of?
DM: Yeah, you could go over here.
DM: Uh,
DM: you can't get far enough to do thunder wave and get this one without getting Wellby, though, unless you go run straight past it into the middle.
Seeker: Wait.
Seeker: Ugh.
Delwath: That seems risky.
Seeker: Yeah, yeah.
Delwath: Wait, you can move through a friendly square.
Delwath: Go one, two-
Seeker: There we go
Delwath: ... three-
Seeker: That's what I should do
Delwath: ... four, five. You might not be able to get...
Delwath: Uh, you might not be quite close enough, 'cause you'd only get to here.
Delwath: You get to that square.
Seeker: That's actually... I'll hit two of them.
Delwath: Right. I don't think you get this guy, but you still get two of them.
Delwath: You'll hit two of them and Delwath.
Delwath: Oh, no, don't hit me.
DM: [laughs]
Seeker: Well, no, but it's only 15.
Seeker: It's only three by three, right?
Wellby: Hmm.
DM: Uh, it's, it's,
DM: it's a-
Delwath: Yeah, no, you would hit, you would hit me.
Delwath: One, two, three.
DM: Yeah. It's one, two, three.
Delwath: It's three squares out in every direction except diagonal from there.
DM: Right.
Delwath: Yeah, you need to go one extra step.
Delwath: You just don't have enough reach to quite make it.
Seeker: Hmm.
Wellby: You... One solid hit on the guy next to me may take him out.
Delwath: Yeah.
Wellby: If you want to-
Delwath: You could just, you know...
Delwath: Um,
Delwath: I'd prefer not to be blasted by a thunder wave.
Seeker: So wait, you're suggesting I go over in, over here?
Wellby: Or even just two to the right.
Wellby: Like, two steps to the right and whack this guy, if you just-
Delwath: Or y- I mean, you could use a, like, a different spell if you have a cantrip or something that doesn't...
Seeker: Not really.
Seeker: Um,
Seeker: sorry.
Seeker: Uh, I'm still a little unclear on the spatial arrangement.
Seeker: So, like, if I did it from where I'm standing right now, it would affect things that are in, like...
Delwath: It'd affect everything three squares away from you.
Seeker: Oh, see, that's not my understanding of what it says.
Seeker: A 15 cube foot, 15-foot cube originating from you, it doesn't travel 15 feet.
Seeker: It's 15 feet on its own.
Delwath: Oh, it's an entire cube.
Seeker: I th- so I, that's why I'm saying it's like a t- a tic-tac-toe board.
Seeker: It's a three by three box.
Seeker: But is that not what you-
Kenzo: No, no, you're right. You're right
Seeker: ... 15-
Delwath: A 15-foot cube originating from you.
Seeker: So, like, if I'm here, I'll hit only the, this little-
Delwath: No, if you were standing where we suggested, you'd only hit, you wouldn't hit them.
Delwath: You'd only hit-
DM: Right, so it's, so it's...
Seeker: I, I wanna go over here.
Seeker: That's what I'm gonna do.
Delwath: It's nine squares total.
DM: Right.
Seeker: Yeah.
DM: So you could, if you do that, you just hit this one here.
Seeker: Yeah. That's what-
DM: But you wouldn't hit anybody else.
Seeker: That's my plan.
DM: Okay.
Seeker: So now I, I do...
Seeker: Okay. So I, um,
Seeker: oh, man.
Seeker: Uh, I reach, I r- I run over past, who's that?
Seeker: Wellby. Um, and, uh, reach high in the air, draw a, a symbol that, uh, screams bright points of light
Seeker: s- spiraling down towards the ground, and then with a great effort of my entire body, thrust it down into the earth, and, uh, a deafening sound erupts all around
Seeker: me.
Wellby: Can I say, incidentally, I love, like, this descriptive, um, combat.
Wellby: Like, rather than just, like, "I cast a thing."
Wellby: Like, that's awesome.
Delwath: Yeah.
DM: Okay. It, it fails, it, it's a constitution save.
DM: It fails its save, um, so you watch as this, like, wave of, this booming wave of thunder, um, expands out from Seeker,
DM: knocking into this lizard and just knocking it over and rolling it 10 feet in this direction as it ends dead on its back at Delwath's
DM: feet, um, pushed by this, like, thunderous crack of sound.
DM: Um, these two, um, look up at this noise and, um, look slightly stunned, and this, uh, sort of deep, um, rumbling
DM: comes low from them, and they just, this, like, low growl starts to build as they now turn and look at Seeker.
Seeker: Oh, shit.
DM: Kenzo, you're up.
Delwath: Wait, this one's dead, right?
DM: This one's dead, yeah.
Kenzo: Oh, so th- that's dead.
Delwath: This guy is full strength, right?
Delwath: That's, yeah, we haven't hurt anybody else.
DM: Nobody else has been hurt, but one is dead.
Kenzo: All right. Yeah. So I step up-
Unknown: ... here, and, um,
Kenzo: take my staff and start, uh, doing a couple of, uh, of kind of, uh, you know, preparatory patterns as I get into a motion, and then slash down at it with all
Unknown: my strength.
Unknown: And... Let's see.
Unknown: [graphics blooping] Now.
Unknown: Oh.
Seeker: Whoa. [laughs]
Unknown: Nice. Nice.
Seeker: That was, uh, inspired.
Kenzo: I'm kicking ass in fighting for some reason.
Unknown: Kenzo's just-
Seeker: Yeah?
Unknown: Kenzo's on fire.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: He just is spinning quarter staff and then just, you know, bam, like swiftly strack- striking right, right on the back of the lizard's head.
DM: So you can make another... You can make your, um, unarmed strike as a bonus action from extra attacks.
Unknown: Right. So this is, this is unarmed strike. Right.
Unknown: Okay.
Seeker: He's gonna punch the lizard in the face.
Kenzo: Yeah. And then smack, and then again, reeling back around, um,
Unknown: and-
DM: Uh, that is gonna miss, however.
Kenzo: Oh, I get bardic ins- or I get the roll, so.
DM: Oh, you get bardic inspiration.
DM: Yes, you can roll, uh-
Seeker: If, if you want it. You get it once in 10 minutes.
Seeker: Is that right?
DM: Yeah, and then it's gone.
Kenzo: Oh, shit. I can only do it once?
Unknown: Uh.
Wellby: You can go for it.
DM: Yeah, but I'd go f-
Unknown: Go for it?
DM: Go for it.
Seeker: Nice. Yeah.
DM: 'Cause I think if you...
Delwath: I think this guy's probably... They didn't take that many hits to kill.
Seeker: Yeah.
Kenzo: How do I, uh... How do I do a D6?
DM: Just type-
Seeker: Uh-
DM: /roll
DM: 1D6.
DM: [intense music]
Seeker: Oh, that hits.
Unknown: Yes. [laughs]
Seeker: Nice. [laughs] And-
Kenzo: Slashing him with the back of my, my, my, uh, my staff, spinning around in one fluid motion with the back of my hand.
Kenzo: Boom. Hitting him again.
Seeker: The rune glowing on your forehead.
Kenzo: The rune glowing on my... Yes, definitely.
Seeker: [laughs]
DM: [laughs] You see what I just sent you?
Unknown: Uh-oh.
Unknown: What? All right.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: So you watch-
Unknown: All right
DM: ... as the one in front of, of Kenzo
DM: falls to the ground
DM: dead with that final strike, powered by the bardic rune.
DM: And then,
DM: Kenzo?
Kenzo: And then you see Kenzo, again, just moving incredibly fast, like faster than you feel like you've seen.
Seeker: Wait, what? [laughs]
Kenzo: Like, he starts moving incredibly fast, hands whipping in a, in a flurry, and then ba, ba, ba, ba, ba, another series of, of strikes into the same, into the same lizard.
Kenzo: And I fuck him up again. Geez.
Unknown: Keep rolling me that.
Seeker: [laughs]
DM: That one also hits. So you watch as Kenzo, like in a, uh, like with this extra burst of speed, like
DM: knocks this lizard down and then, like almost faster than you can see, goes streaking past it and hits a third one, yet again, um, with his fist moving,
DM: moving in this like blazing speed.
DM: The lizard then, like rears up
DM: confused,
DM: and reaches out to bite you, uh, missing.
DM: Delwath, you're up.
Wellby: Whoa.
Delwath: All right. So Delwath will...
Delwath: His sword is out, and he r- he charges forward
Delwath: to there, and then, um, you see a crackling green flame.
Delwath: Um, oh, actually there's n- never mind, there's no point.
Delwath: Um, they... I take that back.
Delwath: He just, he just attacks with the sword.
Unknown: [intense music]
DM: Um, that hits.
DM: Are you,
DM: are you attacking one or two-handed?
Unknown: Uh, two-handed.
DM: Okay.
DM: This, this-
Unknown: And-
DM: ... lizard now looks almost dead.
Unknown: And wait, hold on. It takes the...
Delwath: So y- um, as he's, as he's running, as Delwath is running towards it, he mutters an incantation-
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: ... under his breath, um,
Delwath: and moves the hex [graphics blooping] to this guy.
DM: Ah, okay. Oh, unfortunately that's not quite enough, though.
DM: Okay, so as this like dark energy like crackles the lizard's skin, it again rears back and roars, and now looks like very close near death, and is like looking around,
DM: um, trying to see who or what it can attack next.
DM: But this one's dead.
DM: Wellby, you're up.
Wellby: All right. Without taking my eye off that one, I scoot sideways, scuffling and sidestepping, staying low to the ground, and, uh, pull another arrow
Wellby: and shoot in one, uh, fluid motion.
Wellby: [intense music]
Unknown: Nice.
DM: And that is going to expire the lizard, as your arrow strikes true, and the final lizard with like, foaming at the mouth,
DM: like blood coming out of its, out of its mouth as it's like still in its last moments, like looking around for something to bite, something to attack.
DM: Um, your arrow strikes it in the throat and it slumps to the ground.
Seeker: Whoa.
Wellby: Right.
Unknown: Good job, guys.
Wellby: Good fighting. Yeah.
Seeker: But what were those things?
Delwath: So they seem to be like fiercely interested in attacking whoever last killed them.
Delwath: Is that normal? Whoever last hurt them, is that normal?
DM: No, that's very much not normal behavior for animals.
Unknown: That's what I thought.
DM: You would expect them to, uh, sustaining that damage, flee, or at least, you know, not necessarily charge straight at you.
Unknown: Hm.
DM: That's... You don't even need a nature to...
DM: That's like just-
Unknown: Yeah. Obvious
DM: ... q- quite obvious.
Seeker: So maybe they have unusual intelligence.
Unknown: Or they've been
Delwath: enchanted, or enraged, or drugged, or-
Seeker: Hm
Unknown: ... been told somehow.
Unknown: Um.
Seeker: Okay, let's, uh, inspect some carcasses.
Seeker: That was-
Unknown: Yes
Seeker: ... what we were doing before.
Unknown: And, and-
DM: Well, I'm gonna go-
Kenzo: Go ahead. I just say, I just, I look over at you all as I'm looking down at this one, and I just say, "Are they magic?
Unknown: Are they enchanted?"
Seeker: Hmm, I was wondering that.
Seeker: Um,
Seeker: is it, do you think it's safe for me to do my, my ritual now?
Kenzo: Simas, are, are there any other creatures, anything else around anymore?
DM: Uh, the night is still and quiet at this point.
DM: Um-
Seeker: Yeah.
DM: You know, at the moment of the blast of thunder, there was a sort of a burst of, of some birds and, you know, small animals kind of moving away.
DM: But at this point, it is
DM: just dead and quiet.
Delwath: And nobody came out of tents or anything to investigate, obviously?
DM: Nobody came out of the tents.
Wellby: I, I'll say, "You check the bodies, I'll check the tents."
Seeker: All right.
Delwath: Delwath will also come over and, and start, um,
Delwath: start kind of peering over one of the bodies and kind of getting into a...
Delwath: And it looks like he's going into a little bit of a trance, and sort of
Kenzo: muttering under his breath.
Kenzo: Wellby, Wellby, I'll come inside of the bodies to look at the tents.
DM: So, okay, so-
Unknown: Um.
DM: Wellby and Kenzo are searching the tents.
DM: Um,
DM: Seeker and Delwath are
DM: ritual casting detect magic.
DM: Is that the story?
Unknown: Wow. Base sight, but yeah.
DM: Oh, right. Okay.
Seeker: So I, I'm standing in the center of the, the, the lizard corpses and, uh, drawing a, a giant figure in the, in the, uh, desert
Seeker: sand around my body.
DM: Uh, you do not, um, neither of you perceive anything to be magical about the lizards.
DM: Um,
DM: uh, so
DM: yeah, you don't, you don't get the sense that there's any magic here.
DM: Uh, those of you who are investigating the tents, um,
DM: there is, there is nobody, um, in the tents.
DM: Um, there are, um...
DM: It's dark, so it's not easy to kind of, uh, see tracks or anything, but the tents seem to be somewhat torn up, and there's a, you know, signs of, of scuffle
DM: around here.
DM: Um, there's not a lot of, of gear and equipment, but, um, there is...
DM: I mean, this clearly was a camp that somebody was using recently, so, you know.
DM: In one of the tents, you find some, some water skins and some yogurt and cheese and dried meat and other kinds of supplies.
DM: Um, enough for a, for a decent number of people.
DM: Um, but no, uh, no horses, um, no, uh,
DM: um,
DM: packs or things like that.
Kenzo: Does it look like they, um, like they fled?
Kenzo: Does it look like they're coming back?
Kenzo: Does it look like they're...
Unknown: You know what I mean? Is it, is it like they
Unknown: s-
DM: Um, so-
Unknown: On the...
DM: So make a, uh, I guess a perception check, but with disadvantage 'cause it's dark and you're tired.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Can I, can I, uh, turn, can I use a torch, get some light?
DM: Yeah. So you can, I mean, you can light a torch, right?
DM: You can sort of look around, but, you know, that's only casting light in a, about a 15, 20-foot circle around you, and so the whole scene is, is sort of difficult to,
DM: um-
Wellby: Is the, is that a fire pit in the middle?
DM: There is a fire pit there, yes.
DM: It's, it's-
Wellby: Are there embers, or is it warm at all?
Wellby: Like-
DM: Uh, it is not, it is not warm.
DM: There are, there is, uh, burnt, uh,
DM: burnt log or burnt material in it.
DM: There's like ash in it, but nothing warm.
DM: There definitely wasn't a fire here recently.
DM: You can see, in the dark, you can see that there are like scattered tracks around.
DM: Um, but you can't really make out much of anything,
DM: um,
DM: without, without the light of morning and a clearer mind.
Kenzo: Wellby, I look over at you.
Unknown: Uh, what do you think?
Unknown: You think they fled?
Unknown: You think they're coming back?
Wellby: Kind of put together the timeline.
Seeker: Hmm.
Wellby: Maybe they attacked in the afternoon or the morning?
Wellby: I-
DM: So if you recall, um, so Alesh told you that she had left here early in the morning, and there were people camped there
DM: last night.
Wellby: I'm inclined. I'm inclined to relight the fire and set up
Wellby: a site for ourselves here and see if anyone makes their way back.
Seeker: I like that.
Unknown: How long have the sheep been dead?
Unknown: Like-
DM: Uh-
Unknown: Like
Unknown: days, hours?
Delwath: Are they still freshly bleeding?
DM: Um, not, definitely not days.
DM: Um, in, in the hours range, but you're not sure exactly.
DM: Without a more careful investigation, you're not sure exactly whether that's like two hours or-
Delwath: Well, I'll, I'll do a more careful investigation
DM: ... a lot of hours. Um, okay. Uh, how about medicine?
Delwath: Uh, not nature? All right, I'll go with medicine.
Unknown: I don't have a very good medicine check.
Seeker: [laughs] Hmm.
DM: Uh, you're... Hours, you know.
Unknown: Yeah, hours.
Kenzo: And, uh, now that things feel calm, I'm gonna wander back over to the bodies.
Kenzo: You just see Kenzo just sort of like walking back over to look at, look at the bodies for a moment, the lizard bodies.
Wellby: I'm gonna start gathering fuel for the fire, but not lighting it yet.
DM: Okay.
Seeker: Hmm.
DM: Anything anybody else wants to do?
Unknown: Yeah, Tim, I sent you a message.
DM: Ah, hold on. Let me, let me check something.
Unknown: Oh, checking something.
Seeker: Oh, boy.
Delwath: Are there other campsites nearby?
DM: Um,
DM: so
DM: there is not, there's not ano- ...
DM: So on the far side of the oasis, if you just circumnavigate the entire pool, um, there are some, uh, like more permanent stone structures
DM: that seem to be, you know, occasionally also used as, uh, like sleeping areas or, or pens for animals.
DM: Um, like there's a stone pen and, um, and two wells that are adjacent to the oasis.
DM: The oasis seems a bit muddy.
DM: It's probably mostly, uh, animals that drink there, and humans would draw water from one of these two wells.
DM: Um, but these don't seem to have been...
DM: There's not supplies and stuff set up over here.
DM: There, there, there-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... may have been animals in the pen, but there's not more tents, and there's not obvious indication, um, that there was another group of people here.
Seeker: Hmm.
Delwath: I mean, I think we s- probably just set up camp then and, uh, could use rest anyway.
Seeker: Yep.
DM: Agreed.
Unknown: And then he, uh-
DM: Yep, I'm, I'm getting back to you.
DM: Uh.
DM: [sighs]
DM: Um.
Wellby: Well, no signs of the people who were here being...
Delwath: No, there's no... They seem to have fled, not been killed, right?
Delwath: As far as we can tell.
DM: As far as you can tell. There's no, there's no bodies in the, in the tent or in the campsite.
Kenzo: So Kenzo, you see Kenzo, you know, kind of stroll back into the camp.
Kenzo: You guys are setting up camp now here at the same site?
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Yeah.
Kenzo: Kenzo, Kenzo walks over.
Unknown: Um,
Kenzo: "Good idea. This is a good idea to rest here I think too.
Unknown: I have to say though,
Kenzo: there's something strange about these lizards.
Kenzo: I, it's hard for me to place, but doesn't...
Kenzo: They, they don't, they're, they weren't acting normally.
Kenzo: There's something, there's something off about them.
Kenzo: I don't know if it's the same, the same problem with those, uh, those hyenas, but it's just something's not right."
Seeker: I'm gonna, um,
Seeker: uh,
Seeker: get comfortable by the f- the fire and unroll some...
Seeker: Actually, no, I'll use my, my notebook, and I'm starting to, to sketch as detailed a picture of one of the lizards as I can.
Seeker: Uh, and I think about it a little bit of like, and put on the, on the page facing it one of the hyenas as well.
Unknown: Hmm.
Unknown: Yeah, I definitely-
DM: Seeker, do you-
Unknown: Go ahead, go on.
Kenzo: Seeker, do you think there's a connection between the, the hyena and the lizard?
Seeker: That's what I'm wondering.
Seeker: We don't have much to go on here, do we?
Wellby: Well, both of them are animals that would be native to the area.
Seeker: Hmm.
Wellby: I'm thinking about
Wellby: things that are here already being changed, you know, rather than something coming from elsewhere.
Seeker: That one clue about the hyenas
Seeker: having fought and maybe killed something
Seeker: before they arrived in, name of the city we were just in.
DM: Karawa.
Seeker: Karawa.
Wellby: Mm-hmm.
Seeker: Um, does strike me as odd.
Seeker: We tracked them, but couldn't find much of anything where they might have just been.
Kenzo: I wonder if the source is,
Unknown: is, uh,
Kenzo: something natural or related to humans or something about the town.
Unknown: Delwath, what do you think?
Delwath: They're definitely not acting naturally.
Delwath: I mean, they should've fled
Delwath: when, when we attacked them, right?
Delwath: Not charged the, the last, uh...
Delwath: Did you notice they were, they were actually charging the most recent, um, whoever hurt them last, they, they focused on, they ran towards.
Unknown: But-
Delwath: Most to the exclusion of anything else.
Kenzo: But if they're not enchanted, then what's, what's the source of this,
Unknown: this strange behavior?
Seeker: Hmm.
Delwath: I think somebody wants some th- somebody or something wants them to, to, to rise up, but how they're making it happen, I don't know.
DM: Could it be...
Delwath: Could we, could we dissect one?
DM: I mean, I don't-
Seeker: [laughs]
Delwath: ... don't, don't know that I'd learn anyth- I mean, I, I,
Delwath: not an expert here. I don't know if any of you are experts.
Seeker: If you wanna cut one open, you might wa- wait till the morning.
Delwath: Hmm. Probably, but, but when did it last eat?
Delwath: I don't know. Was it fed something that would...
Seeker: That is an interesting question, actually.
Seeker: If we could get that to work out.
Wellby: Presumably should, but I wonder if there's other stuff beyond that.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Hmm.
Wellby: I wonder also in the morning if we can track them.
Wellby: You know, we lost the hyenas' trail.
Wellby: Maybe we can pick these guys up.
DM: Yeah.
DM: And we'll trace them back in the morning.
Seeker: Hmm.
Seeker: Giant lizards.
Seeker: Do they-
DM: Um-
Seeker: Do they, do they normally live, like, in holes, or do they make nests, or, like, where do lizards even live?
Delwath: Tim, just as an aside.
Unknown: Yeah?
Delwath: I walked around the oasis earlier, but I still had, I was still concentrating on keeping my face sight up.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: I assume there's no magic anywhere around here.
DM: No, there's no magic anywhere.
Delwath: Yeah, there doesn't seem to be any magic that I can see.
Seeker: Mm
Delwath: ... anywhere around here.
Delwath: So, so it's not, I think, that the oasis was enchanted or something like that.
Seeker: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: I wonder if it's, if it's, uh, a natural phenomenon, you know, something that's just occurring on its own, or something more sinister.
Delwath: Has a sinister feel to me.
Wellby: The viciousness of the attack doesn't feel natural.
Seeker: I wonder, too, what, uh, what we should be on the lookout for.
Seeker: Like, what are the other, uh-
Wellby: [laughs]
Seeker: ... creatures that inhabit this area?
Unknown: Well, um-
Delwath: Right, that's a good...
Delwath: Yeah
Seeker: Like, uh, the-
Delwath: Are there any other creatures that live around here that might-
Seeker: Like quintuple-sized predatory birds.
Seeker: That could be uncomfortable to encounter.
Unknown: Um-
Wellby: Carnivorous
DM: ... uh, give, give me a, a nature check for that.
Kenzo: I've got plus three animal handling.
Unknown: Does that help me?
Seeker: [laughs] No.
Delwath: I have plus four nature.
Unknown: Oh, that's good.
Delwath: But I rolled a three.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: Um-
Delwath: So I got a seven. That's not that helpful.
Seeker: Yeah.
Wellby: I think more than anything else, what we need is a good night's sleep right now.
Seeker: Yeah. [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: So, so not, um-
Delwath: Seeker got a 14.
Seeker: That's true.
DM: No, you need... But he's exhausted.
Unknown: You need to roll with disadvantage.
Delwath: Oh, yeah. Roll again, Seeker.
Seeker: Oh, snap.
Seeker: Nature again.
Delwath: Roll, roll better this time.
Seeker: [laughs]
DM: Oh, that's not too bad. So I mean, in your study, Seeker, um, and in your travels to get here, uh-
Seeker: I flip back through my notebook, looking at other creatures
DM: ... right. You, you look back through your notes as...
DM: You're, you're like a little... Your, your eyes are definitely...
DM: Your eyelids are sort of closing a bit, and you're struggling to, to stay awake as the adr- adrenaline from the battle fades.
DM: But you do... So I mean, the things that you might be concerned about, I mean, so there's like hyenas, um,
DM: uh, wild dogs, um, like badgers and snakes.
Unknown: Or not badgers, I guess.
Unknown: Snakes and, um-
Seeker: Snakes
DM: ... uh, s- things like that.
DM: The thing, the thing that's, the, the two things that strike in your memory that, um, seem like they could be the
DM: least pleasant to encounter in an enraged state, if that's what this is, um, would be, uh...
DM: So there are, um, large flightless birds, um,
DM: ostrich-like, but with, uh-
Seeker: [laughs] Ostriches
DM: ... sharp, sharp claws and, and piercingly sharp beaks, called axe beaks, that you probably wouldn't...
DM: I mean, as basically as tall as a person, so bigger than a dwarf.
DM: You probably wouldn't wanna run into them.
Unknown: Um-
Seeker: Lightly roasted, though, they're delicious.
DM: Yes. Um, they make a good, a good dinner.
DM: Um, in fact, some of the dried meat in the tent could be dried axe beak.
Unknown: Um,
DM: the other thing that, um, that comes to your mind that you've heard tell of but haven't actually seen your...
DM: So you would've, you'd seen the axe beak and have a sketch of them.
DM: Um, the other thing you've, you've heard of but haven't, um, haven't seen,
DM: but would be definitely not interested in meeting, are giant scorpions.
Seeker: Oh, God. [laughs]
DM: 10-foot-long, enormous insects that, um, are rumored to roam the desert and poison anything that comes near
DM: them, and then drag the poisoned creatures away to their, um, cave hideouts and let them dry out as meals for their babies.
Seeker: Oh my, oh my God.
DM: Probably would be not so much fun if they were, uh, acting like these lizards acted like.
DM: There's also, like... So there are lions that live in the, in the pl- desert plains.
Unknown: Um,
DM: most everything else would be sort of smaller than a hy- I mean, there's, like, normal-sized scorpions, obviously, as well.
Unknown: Um-
Seeker: Mm-hmm
DM: ... but those are the two that, that immediately come to mind as, like-
Delwath: Come on
Delwath: ... in this state you definitely wouldn't want to
Seeker: Well, good. I'm ready.
Delwath: Right.
Seeker: Well. [laughs]
Delwath: So who's keeping watch first?
Seeker: Oh, man. Wait.
Seeker: It's interesting, though, because if you're, if you're on the lookout, s- l- looking out for scorpions of all sizes,
Seeker: might involve, like,
Seeker: listening for a different set of things.
Seeker: I don't know.
Delwath: Let's get some rest.
Seeker: Yeah.
Wellby: I'll make sure there's enough wood to keep a good fire going all night long, and then take, uh, take first watch.
Unknown: Okay.
Seeker: Excellent.
Unknown: Um, okay. So-
Delwath: Dal- Dalwath will volunteer to take, take the second and third watch.
Unknown: Right, 'cause you don't really need to sleep.
Wellby: Also, side no- new character goal, 100%, is to tame a giant two-legged bird to ride on as a mount.
Delwath: Awesome.
Seeker: [laughs] I love that idea.
DM: That would be a great mount for a halfling.
Seeker: Wow.
Delwath: Yeah, badass.
Seeker: That's awesome.
DM: Okay. So, uh, you can all, um,
DM: do... Y- nothing eventful happens in the night.
DM: Um, it's quiet. You can all click the long rest button.
DM: Should erase exhaustion as well as recovering your spell slots and hit points.
Seeker: Long rest.
Seeker: Take long rest.
Seeker: Oh, wait. Do I have to check off recover one level of exhaustion?
Unknown: Yeah, yes.
Seeker: Okay. Confirm.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: So,
Unknown: um,
DM: early... The morning comes bright and clear.
DM: Um, you feel like it's gonna be another warm, hot day.
DM: Um, as you are, uh...
DM: As the sun rises, um, it's now much more obvious that, uh, the camp itself was the site of some, uh,
DM: extended chaos at some point yesterday, even before you showed up.
DM: You can see, without even having to search, um, the t- the tracks of the giant lizards, um, come from the east-
DM: So they, so from the far side of the oasis, um,
DM: and there seems to be some confusing sort of intersection of, of tracks and, um, marks and things in the ground sort of around the camp.
DM: Uh, some indicating heading sort of north, northwest.
DM: Um, if you'd like to,
DM: uh, if anybody wants to like search or,
DM: you know,
DM: try and investigate more, you can let me know exactly what you're s- kind of looking at.
Unknown: I think we should follow the lizard tracks.
Seeker: I li- I kind of like the idea of slicing open a, a lizard's stomach.
Delwath: Although maybe we should slice open a lizard's stomach first.
Seeker: I, I-
Unknown: Let's do that
Seeker: ... I mean, not personally.
Seeker: Like, I'm interested to like observe from a-
Unknown: Sure
Seeker: ... sort of distance away.
Unknown: And does my a-
Unknown: Also-
Kenzo: ... does my animal handling skill, uh, help me with-
Seeker: [laughs]
Unknown: ... lizards?
Kenzo: Or would nature help?
DM: Uh, um, for sli- for dissecting a lizard, I'm gonna say-
Seeker: That's medicine probably, right?
DM: ... medicine.
Unknown: I got plus three medicine.
DM: So who wants to, who wants to do the dissection?
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: I'll do the checks.
Unknown: Three-
Unknown: I'll do it. I'll do it
Unknown: ... three lizards.
Seeker: It's true. [laughs]
DM: Yeah, you can do it.
Delwath: Can, can I help somebody by making a nature check and giving them, kibitzing from the back and giving them advice?
DM: Yes. Yes, you can do that.
Unknown: All right.
DM: Uh, give, give, give me a nature check for that.
Unknown: 13.
DM: Okay. So whoever...
DM: So, so one person can roll their medicine check with advantage.
Unknown: All right.
Seeker: Well, actually, I'm gonna sit close by and, like, make jokes.
Delwath: I'm gonna, I'm gonna, I'm gonna give, um, uh, Kenzo a lot of advice, and sort of point out when you're, when the various bits that you should be dissecting
Delwath: are. But, you know, sort of letting you do the actual cutting.
Kenzo: I've got some skill. Does anybody have a good knife for this?
Kenzo: I need, I need a good knife. I don't have a good knife.
Delwath: Yeah, I have a kn- I'll give you a dagger.
Kenzo: All right. All right, Tim, um-
Delwath: Or are you... Yeah.
Kenzo: I'm rolling a wisdom? I'm res- I'm rolling a medicine, right?
DM: Yeah. You have advantage 'cause-
Delwath: Yeah. You have advantage. You can roll twice and take the better one.
Unknown: All right. Sweet.
Wellby: I have a, a wonderful time slicing my lizard open, but, uh, very inconclusive results.
Seeker: [laughs]
Unknown: Do it again and see what happens?
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Yeah.
Seeker: You take the better, so...
Unknown: All right.
DM: So, so you spend some time, um, cutting open the lizards.
DM: Uh,
DM: it's...
DM: I mean, they're big. It takes you, it takes you probably a good hour to carefully dissect them.
DM: Um-
Unknown: Damn
DM: ... it's not...
DM: So it's obvious they were eating sheep for a while.
DM: Um-
Seeker: Mm-hmm
DM: ... there's nothing else sort of obvious that you can, um,
DM: you can pull out, like, from their stomachs or anything.
DM: Like, you know, there's some, you know, partially digested meat, but it's not really at all clear what it might be.
DM: Um, there's nothing that strikes you as off particularly, uh, about them, um, as you're, as you're dissecting them e- um, except that,
DM: um,
DM: you know, they seem to be,
DM: uh, so like the, uh, hyenas.
DM: It, there's like, you do see, like, there's a bit of...
DM: And it's a little bit hard to tell exactly if this is from the sheep or from something else, but there's, like, dried blood in their claws.
DM: Uh, you know, one of them has a, has a bit of a, um, a scar on its side that seems to have started to heal a little bit and,
DM: you know, probably wasn't from yesterday.
DM: Uh,
DM: but it's a little bit hard for you to be exactly sure.
Seeker: Hmm.
Delwath: So they've been in a fight before.
Unknown: With what?
Unknown: Maybe somebody's...
Delwath: Too bad we don't have, you know...
Delwath: Can we, like, invent gene sequencing and sequence-
Seeker: [laughs]
Delwath: ... the DNA of the blood so we can tell if it's lizard blood or human blood?
DM: Uh, nope.
Kenzo: Can anybody recognize what... Does anybody, can anybody distinguish what kind of blood this is?
DM: No, I mean-
Delwath: Lizard blood's not, like, green or something like that, right?
DM: No, it's not. There's nothing, like, obvious about it that you could, um,
DM: you know.
Wellby: But, but Tim, they, like, they have all their normal parts.
Unknown: Like, they're-
DM: Yes
Unknown: ... they're normal lizards.
DM: To the extent that you've, you know, cut up lizards before, this seems like what you'd expect would happen if you cut up a lizard.
Seeker: [laughs] And I now, I now have detailed anatomical drawings-
Unknown: Yes, you do
Seeker: ... for future reference.
Kenzo: Fuck yeah. Your, your paper is coming out of this shit, you're gonna be dope, dude.
Seeker: [laughs] That was so out there.
DM: So, so as you're, um, as you're, uh, cleaning up, uh, the,
DM: you know, cleaning your daggers and stuff and, um, you know, just getting cleaned up a little bit, uh, from the, the sort of blood and gore of doing this dissection,
DM: um, you see, uh, on the horizon, a man on horseback sort of riding towards the oasis slowly, um, and sort of
DM: s- uh, seems like he's traveling sort of cautiously in this direction.
Unknown: Coming from where?
DM: That seems to have... Coming from the northwest.
DM: Doesn't seem to have s- noticed you yet.
DM: He just, there's, like, a little bit of a hilly, uh, you know, a few, like, rises of the ground in that direction.
Unknown: So-
DM: I mean, he's just crested the, the hill
Delwath: ... for, for those of us who can't remember the geography, northwest is...
Delwath: Where are we compared to the town?
DM: The northwest would be, uh...
DM: So the town, I mean, you're about two days travel from the town.
Unknown: Sure.
DM: Day and a half travel. The town is southwest of you.
Seeker: This is somebody who fled last night.
DM: The lizard tracks run roughly east.
DM: So there's an old trade road that you've been following.
DM: The oasis is on this old trade road.
DM: The lizard tracks seem to run east along the trade road.
DM: Um, this, this man is coming not from the trade road, but from the open plains, uh, to the, to the, um, north and west-
Delwath: Okay, if it-
DM: ... of the oasis
Delwath: ... there's nothing like, it's not like there's something...
Delwath: We'd be... Is it a dir- I'm trying to figure out is the direction we'd be expecting somebody to be coming from.
Delwath: Or we would have no idea.
DM: Ah, you would have no idea.
Delwath: Is there like-
DM: We wouldn't-
Delwath: There's not like another village there that we know about or...
DM: No. I mean, so this, this area, in the morning light you can tell that the area around the oasis seems to be, um, greener and grassier and
DM: less deserty than sort of what you were tr- I mean, it's not bare rock.
DM: Like, uh, you know, two days ago you were traveling through these sort of bare canyon lands.
Delwath: Right.
DM: Um, this is definitely, you know, seems like, and especially going off north of the road, um, it just seems a little bit wetter.
Delwath: Mm-hmm.
DM: Uh, it's a little bit lower ground.
DM: Um, it's definitely an area where people, you know, a lot of the D- you know, the Dunmari are largely pastoralists, right?
Delwath: Right.
DM: So-
Delwath: So-
DM: ... it would not be at all surprising that somebody might be-
Delwath: Yeah, right, right,
Delwath: right. Should we hail him?
Kenzo: What was the name of the... Do you remember, uh, um, this, the, the la- the lady on the horse?
Kenzo: She was like, "Oh, when you go to the oasis, talk to this guy."
Delwath: Oh, yeah.
DM: What was the name of that guy again?
DM: Akan.
Unknown: Akan.
Kenzo: And she, and Akan was what relation to her again?
DM: No relation. They just had-
Unknown: Just somebody
DM: ... she had just spent the night at the oasis.
Unknown: Okay.
Delwath: Okay. I think we should hail this guy.
Unknown: Let's do it.
Delwath: So I'll like, you know, go up to a, a high point, you know, or, or walk out a little bit from the tent and call out to him.
DM: Cool. Uh, okay.
DM: As you, um,
DM: as you call out, he, he sees you and kind of pulls up his horse for a minute and, and looks around, sort of takes in the scene for a minute, and then,
DM: um, starts, uh, his horse back up a tro- like, gives you a, a wave once he sees you're human and un- and s- unhurt, um, and starts, uh,
DM: his horse at a trot coming down into the oasis.
DM: So as he approaches, he, um,
DM: he looks
DM: weary and tired, and there's, um, he has a bandage around his arm, uh, and it's, it seems like, uh, he was wounded at some point recently.
DM: And as he swings down off of his horse, um,
DM: he's, he's limping a little bit, and he looks around at you and he says,
DM: "The creatures,
DM: they are gone?"
Delwath: We killed three of them last night.
Delwath: Were there more than that?
DM: No, I do not belie- well, there was one we killed at great cost.
DM: And he sort of, uh, pauses for a moment and, um, sort of tears well up in his eyes a little bit.
DM: Uh,
DM: uh, he says, "But no, we only ever saw four.
DM: If you've killed three, then, then perhaps it is indeed safe to return."
Kenzo: What's your name, traveler?
DM: Uh, he si- he sighs for a moment and he says, um, "Akan.
DM: My name is Akan.
DM: And you?"
Kenzo: Kenzo. Uh, what was the name of the, the scout lady again?
DM: Alesh.
Unknown: Alesh.
Kenzo: Uh, Kenzo, and we met your, your, your comrade, Alesh, yesterday
Kenzo: riding, riding back towards town.
DM: She is safe?
DM: She's safe?
Delwath: She was last night, or yesterday morning.
Delwath: Who knows these days-
DM: He, he kind of-
Delwath: ... she still is
DM: ... um, like leans heavily on his horse again, and,
DM: "She, she made a lucky decision.
DM: It was just past lunchtime as we were resting, uh, in the hottest part of the day when these creatures came.
DM: Four of them
DM: running,
DM: driving up a cloud of dust down the road, like nothing I'd ever seen."
Delwath: Oh.
DM: "Do not know why they were so,
DM: so enraged, so bloodthirsty."
Delwath: Hmm.
DM: "We thought we could scare them off.
DM: My family, there was 11 of us.
DM: Only seven now remain."
Delwath: Wow.
DM: And he, like, pauses and takes a deep breath again, and he says, "We,
DM: we fled as we could into the hills with no supplies, no water, no food.
DM: So had to come...
DM: But on horseback we were able to escape the, these creatures do not move so fast.
DM: Those of us who are alive, anyway," he says, like, you know, voice cracking a little bit.
DM: "But we had to, we cannot make it to town without, without water, without food.
DM: Two-day journey through the, through the wild.
DM: There's no place to get, to get water between here and Karawa.
DM: So I came back to see.
DM: Thank you, thank you
DM: for killing those creatures. If they were still here,
DM: I'm not sure what we would have done.
DM: I guess
DM: probably died in the desert."
DM: And sort of drifts off a little bit at that point.
Delwath: Are you from Kar- Karawa?
DM: Uh, hmm.
DM: I guess not from exactly.
DM: Uh, you know, we, we have tend to go back there every year for the market and festival coming up.
DM: But mostly travel in the, in the northern parts of, of this country, um, grazing our sheep and horses.
DM: Um,
DM: you know, the, the losses are
DM: hard to reckon with right now, but sheep at least can be replaced, our horses can be replaced.
Unknown: Hmm.
DM: We had thought to rest a few days by the oasis with the good grazing land here,
DM: and, uh,
DM: make our way, uh, you know, take our leisure for a little while and make our way to town for the festival in a few weeks.
DM: But it seems that was a poor choice.
Unknown: Where are your comrades?
DM: Hiding in the hills just north of here.
DM: Did not think it was worth the risk, all of us coming in.
DM: I was just scouting.
DM: On a horse I'm confident I could outrun any of these creatures.
Unknown: They came from the east?
DM: They came from the east,
DM: along the road.
Unknown: Well, hopefully-
Unknown: I heard
Unknown: ... it's safe to bring them back.
Delwath: Uh, have you, have you heard of the hyena attacks?
DM: I have not.
DM: Are there creatures attacking?
Unknown: In Karawa.
Unknown: Kara- Kara-
Unknown: Karawa. K- Karawa
Unknown: ... Karawa.
Delwath: There's been several, uh, several hyena attacks on town.
Delwath: The last and, and worst, um,
Unknown: uh,
Delwath: unusually large creatures with of unusual ferocity.
DM: As, as you're talking, he's like, it, it, it seems like he's getting over the sort of shock and surprise a little bit, and he's looking
DM: a- around at all of you, and kind of takes a step back and says,
DM: "Creatures of myth and legend walking in this land."
DM: Is it-
Delwath: Delwath just bows slightly and says, "Delwath, the elf, I'm called in these parts."
DM: I had heard rumor such a thing
DM: was living in Karawa.
DM: I did not expect to see so myself.
DM: And you, a Dunmari, traveling with these strange folk," he says, looking at Kenzo.
DM: And you've all been talking in Dunmari, so he was like, took him a minute for his brain to catch up with the fact that you are,
DM: you know, not what he was expecting.
Unknown: Hmm.
Seeker: Unusual band for an unusual time.
Kenzo: Um, Kenzo kind of looks at, uh, you know, the three of you.
Kenzo: Um, should we, should we take them back to town?
Kenzo: Looks like this is...
Kenzo: Or should we still try to work more out here?
DM: Do you have-
Unknown: Uh
DM: ... He's looks at you as he, like, hears you s- I assume you're still speaking in Dunmari here.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: As you say that, he says, "Do you have horses?"
Unknown: Just one.
DM: No.
Unknown: Go, go get your...
Delwath: I think go get your companions, and we'll at least stay here and, and make sure it stays safe until you've set out.
Unknown: Yeah. All your provisions are still here.
DM: That is a relief.
DM: Um, and he s- as he's, he says, "I will be back shortly."
DM: And he says, as he's, as he's riding off, he says, "Did you,
DM: did any of you find a, a small amulet, a wooden, um, a wooden circulet?
DM: It was my, it was my sister's.
DM: A, a, uh, holy symbol of, of, um..."
DM: Oops, sorry, where is my notes?
DM: "...
DM: Of Chidya, who was precious to her.
DM: She lost it, uh,
DM: running, and
DM: if it turned up, I would be most grateful."
Seeker: We haven't seen it, but we can look around.
Unknown: We'll look.
Unknown: We'll search for it.
DM: He says, "I will be, I will be back soon," and he rides off.
Unknown: Well-
Unknown: A woman wearing a nice circlet, huh?
Delwath: Any signs of the... I mean, in daylight, if we search again, any signs of-
DM: Yeah, uh, in day- I mean, n- i- if you take some time and actually, like, look around the camp in daylight, it's, it's obvious that there's, um, you know, you find some more stuff kind
DM: of scattered around. There's a, there's a small purse that was ripped open, and, um, a handful of small silver and copper coins are scattered around.
DM: Um,
DM: in addition to the food sort of outside, you know, scattered a little bit outside the tent, um, you know, there's somebody's, somebody's backpack, uh,
DM: ripped open, and there's some traveling clothes and things strewn.
DM: And you do find this, um, intricately, small, intricately carved wooden amulet that's like four s- strands braided together to form a circle, um,
DM: which is the, the holy symbol of, of Chidya, who's the goddess of nature and land and animals and the seasons.
DM: Um, so it seems like, you know, there was definitely...
DM: The, the feeling you get from searching around is that there was, like, a panicked rush as people were jumping on their horses and running, and so there was some stuff that was, was scattered around.
DM: But it's pretty easy in daylight and with some time to, like, collect it all and, um,
DM: you know, put it with the food and the water that was stored in the tents.
Seeker: Yeah, we can generally kind of clean up the area.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Maybe, um,
Seeker: remove the remnants of the dissection process.
Unknown: And Mar-
DM: Is there anything... Go ahead.
Kenzo: I was gonna say, are there, is there, are there more dwellings, like, anywhere?
Unknown: Is, is, is, like, this the main camp?
Kenzo: Do we see anything else kind of near us when we-
DM: So again, in the daylight, you can see there were more tents, um, that were, seemed like they were destroyed- There was at least three more large tents that were destroyed
DM: by the lizards.
Seeker: Hmm.
DM: There was probably at least six tents here, three of which remain standing, um,
DM: three of which were just kind of ripped to pieces at some point.
Seeker: Mm-hmm.
DM: There's also a lot more dead sheep apparent in the daylight.
DM: Um, some that had fled, fled, sort of started to flee north, and then seemed like they were attacked,
DM: um, by a lizard that was killed, which you, you find the one dead, another dead lizard about, um,
DM: you know, 200 yards to the north following the tracks where there's another large collection of dead sheep.
Seeker: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: So are we at the edge of the oasis, or is this like...
Kenzo: How big is the oasis, and where are we relative to it?
DM: Uh, so the, the pool itself is, uh, maybe 60 feet across, like a 60-foot oval.
DM: Um, it's not huge, but it's clear that there's a underground reservoir of water here, because the sort of greener grass extends maybe a quarter mile.
DM: Like, you can, like, you're in a little bit of a depression.
DM: There's hills that are sort of rolling hills to the north, and this area is just much greener, right?
DM: There's, there's some trees in the distance you can see.
DM: There's, um, there's bits of grass.
DM: There's decent grazing land here.
DM: There's, of course, the string of trees and plants right along the water as well.
DM: Um...
Seeker: I'll investigate for any geological anomalies.
DM: Uh, so,
DM: uh, make an intelligence check.
DM: Just straight intelligence.
Seeker: Solid.
Unknown: Intelligent.
Seeker: [laughs]
DM: Yep.
Wellby: I'll be right back, guys. Don't wait on me.
DM: Okay.
Seeker: Cool.
Seeker: Huh.
Seeker: So I'm kind of like
Seeker: searching around, looking at the edge of the oasis, kind of like
Seeker: poking at things.
Seeker: Uh, and I start to go inc- grow increasingly puzzled.
Seeker: Um,
Seeker: it just seems like a weird place for an oasis.
Seeker: [laughs]
DM: I'm, I'm typing more.
DM: I, I caught that. Um...
Seeker: Okay.
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: Oh, good, 'cause that was all I had for a second.
Kenzo: I'm making myself a snack, but I'm, I'm on...
Unknown: I can listen and hear everything.
Seeker: Okay.
Unknown: I'll be back in a second.
Seeker: Very important.
Wellby: Take some time to map out our environs in my
Wellby: mapping cartography
Wellby: ley line.
Wellby: So Tim, they... These lizards killed like way more sheep than they were possibly gonna eat.
DM: Yes, very much way more sheep than they could have possibly eaten.
Seeker: Hmm.
Seeker: But they traveled by road.
DM: Uh, yes. They seem to tr- have traveled by road.
Seeker: Hmm.
Seeker: So there's a weird, um, transition area
Seeker: between the canyons and the edge of the oasis, the canyons
Seeker: south of us.
Seeker: So I'm gonna,
Seeker: I'm gonna go, try to get to that transition region, like where the grassy area starts, and see if I can find anything strange about it.
DM: It, it's not, it's, it's not so much that there's a, um,
DM: there's like a single point that is odd.
DM: It's just the,
DM: uh, it's just the, um...
DM: Right? Like, oases, naturally speaking, you would expect oases to be sort of in the middle of a desert, but it's like a,
DM: you know, um, the way that it shifts now much more, it's not just the oasis, right?
DM: It's like, almost like there's sort of rolling hills and grassland here and, and rocky desert south of the road a few miles.
DM: It's like a, a juxtaposition that strikes you as kind of like, like the oasis is some kind of transition point or something in, in a geography that is not,
DM: or a geology that is not completely, um,
DM: determined by natural forces.
DM: If that makes sense.
Seeker: Like, like maybe the oasis is kind of an intrusion, like it was put here.
DM: Either that or the rocky canyon is kind of an intrusion.
Seeker: Hmm.
DM: Right? It's a little bit hard to tell one way or the other.
DM: Like-
Seeker: Hmm
DM: ... something doesn't quite match up.
DM: Um.
Seeker: Mm-hmm. Is the
Seeker: ground of the oasis area, like, literally made of a, of a different type of stone?
DM: Um,
DM: no. It all seems to be,
DM: uh... It's just, there's just more, it's more s- like sandy dirt.
DM: Um.
Seeker: Mm-hmm.
DM: Right? But it's not, it's...
DM: What's strange about it is that if you just, um, so if all the canyons and things were just created by water eroding, you'd expect
DM: a different topography here.
DM: It's almost like something stripped away the dirt and the grass and stuff from the south and just exposed all the rock, and it's not just, like, natural erosion.
DM: And looking at the oasis, you're like, "This," like, "this seems like it's from a different desert."
DM: Right? A much wetter and less- And much, much more hospitable desert than
DM: where you were the middle of the afternoon yesterday or two days ago.
Seeker: So maybe this is an area that was protected from some catastrophic process.
Seeker: It's a little bubble.
DM: It's hard to tell exactly.
DM: I mean, you, you'd have to spend, you know, a day or two sort of charting everything.
Seeker: Mm.
DM: Going around and, you know,
DM: you know. But it's really what strikes you is in the light of day looking at the, um, looking at the area around this oasis and the terrain extending north, it just, it just
DM: feels off somehow, like it's not a, a natural
DM: juxtaposition.
Seeker: What's the overall...
Seeker: Can I get a sense of the overall shape of the anomalous area?
DM: N- I mean, it's
DM: n- it's, no. C- I mean, it extends.
DM: It's like looking to the south you see in the distance kind of rocky outcroppings, and looking to the north you see in the distance
DM: rolling hills with scrubby grass on them.
Wellby: Hm. So it's large.
DM: Yeah, it's large. It's like if you took like Texas Hill Country and, um, Joshua Tree National Park and put them next to each other.
Seeker: Mm-hmm.
Seeker: So it's not necessarily specific to the oasis area that we're in?
DM: Yeah, it's just the sort of looking around the oa- l- like thinking about
DM: exploring the oasis and kind of looking a- about looking, sort of trying to understand the geology of it
DM: made you kind of realize this larger picture.
Seeker: Well, I'll, I'll make some, some, some notes and sketches of what I think this transition line looks like.
DM: Okay.
DM: Okay, so as you're doing that, um,
DM: Akan and, uh, the six other surviving men- members of his group, um, return and, and everybody's very grateful and thanks you.
DM: Um,
DM: gather up their food. They have, um,
DM: between them, between all of them, they have eight horses.
DM: So some horses obviously died.
DM: Um, but they have enough for a few...
DM: Sorry, there's seven of them. They have nine horses.
DM: Um, so they have enough for a few people to switch mounts.
DM: Um, Akan basically is like, "There's no way you guys can keep up with us if we're riding fast for Karawa across the plain unless you have your own horses."
Unknown: Now,
Delwath: I, I mean, if he, if they, do, do they feel safe, do they feel safe riding?
Delwath: We suggest, I mean, we would suggest they-
DM: Yeah
Delwath: ... ride fast and stop as little as possible.
DM: They,
DM: I mean, they, they, yes, they f- they felt like once they were able to get on their horses and gather speed on the open plains,
DM: they easily out distanced the lizards.
Delwath: Do you know of, do they know of any other, any other folks out here who might be...
Delwath: Like, were there any tra- other travelers to the oasis recently?
Unknown: Are there-
DM: Only, only Alesh, and she was going to, uh, gather up her extended family and head towards Karawa.
DM: There's other groups out on the plains, right?
DM: Like, it's not-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... it's not, um, none that they've had recent contact with.
Delwath: Right. I, I would, I'll tell them, I'd suggest that anybody they meet, um, it's probably safest to gather
Delwath: soon, now, in Karawa, even if people were planning on waiting a few weeks for the festival.
DM: Yes.
Delwath: The sooner you can gather, the better.
DM: So, so they have, they have, um, Akan has a little conversation with, um,
DM: this young guy who then, um, you know, they have a slight argument and he, uh, is, like, insisting, "Yes, I can do it."
DM: And, um, as you're saying that, um,
DM: Akan then says, uh,
DM: "M- my cousin here, my nephew," sorry, "my nephew here is gonna take, uh, two fresh exchanges of mounts and gallop hard across the plains, changing
DM: horses so he can cover a great distance at speed,
DM: and try and, uh, warn as many people to the north and west of here to hurry back to town.
DM: But I think he'll be able to travel far faster than anybody else with three horses, uh, to change between, and skill in riding.
DM: But thank you for the suggestion."
DM: And he just then immediately, like, takes,
DM: like, some, some water and, and a bit of dried meat and food and just gallops off.
Unknown: Right.
DM: And you see the dust rising bet- behind him with the three horses, um, moving extremely fast.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: So just, like, as we were, before you mo- like, as they had been, as we were just kind of cleaning and, you know, looking for stuff, like, you know, just looking around, like,
Kenzo: just say to everybody, to, to you guys, the party, um, "What else do we have to learn out here, friends?
Unknown: Seeker, have you found anything?"
Seeker: Well, I've been walking the strange edges of this area and wondering how an oasis got here.
Seeker: The, this country has a strange history, that much I, I can tell you for sure.
Kenzo: Hm. Recent history or old history?
Seeker: It's, it's probably like within the past...
Seeker: It's hard to say, because in the natural course of events, [laughs] the landscape changes over millennia.
Seeker: Eons, really.
Unknown: Hm.
Seeker: Uh,
Seeker: but we know that there were great shifts just in the past couple of hundred years in this very place.
Seeker: Isn't that right?
Unknown: Old magic?
Seeker: Yeah.
DM: Old magic
Seeker: So it could be that following the Great War, this landscape was reshaped.
Seeker: And my guess is that things looked in a wide area around where we are, more like they do where we stand
Seeker: than the way they look in that desert that we traversed.
Seeker: Is that basically right, Tim?
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Tim, I, I just, you know, as we're all kind of just talking, like I, I, I asked Akan, um, have you seen anything else strange before these lizards?
Kenzo: Has all of this behavior been of, of these...
Kenzo: You know, you, I know you hadn't heard about the hyenas, but is this all, all recent?
Kenzo: Have you, have you seen anything or heard anything like this about animals, strange animals acting strangely?
DM: There's always strange tales east of Gomat.
Unknown: East of Gomat.
DM: But nothing like this.
DM: W- this is the Gomat Oasis.
DM: It's-
Unknown: And-
DM: ... sort of the border-
Delwath: ... the wizards came from the east, so.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Yeah. The weird stuff is, is that way.
Unknown: I-
Seeker: Um.
Unknown: I think it's worth going-
DM: This is, basically people don't tend to go past east of the oasis, because there's always these tales of, like, people who go out into the, the Blasted
DM: Plains is what they're called, Nashtkar in the Dunmari language, and never return, or come back changed in some way, or, um, come back scarred and won't
DM: talk about what they were, you know, what happened to them.
Unknown: So let's go there.
DM: So most people just don't go there.
Unknown: Right. Let's-
DM: But-
Delwath: ... go to the place nobody goes to and see what's there.
Wellby: Does he know, or is there anyone, are there any settlements, ruins, people, weird old desert hermits who live out that way?
Wellby: I mean, is there, are there any, like, landmarks you can give us to the east?
DM: Um,
DM: he, he, he himself has never been east of, east of here.
DM: This is the furthest east he's traveled.
DM: Um,
DM: this is, there's good grazing land further east, but he refuses to, um, to take his family past here because it seems like it's not safe.
Wellby: We could-
DM: The road continues, and, and you, well, um,
DM: so...
Seeker: We did see that creepy canyon in the distance.
Seeker: That, that I'm sure is a perfectly friendly place.
Wellby: I think we follow the lizard tracks east.
Seeker: Mm.
Kenzo: What was the creepy canyon? Did we see that earlier?
Seeker: Last session.
Unknown: Oh.
Seeker: In the distance.
Kenzo: Okay. And just context again, um, when was the festi- when is the festival happening?
DM: It would be, like, 12 days from now.
DM: It was two weeks when you set out.
Seeker: Yeah. Yeah.
Unknown: And how many days are we away from town?
DM: Uh.
Seeker: Two days?
DM: Two days-ish.
Unknown: All right.
Seeker: Hm.
Kenzo: And other than us, were there, like, warriors or, like, security forces at, in the town?
Kenzo: Like, I remember we kind of showed up and, you know, fucked up the hyenas.
Kenzo: But, like, like, basically is the town safe if we're not, if we're not there?
DM: [coughs]
DM: Um,
DM: I mean,
DM: you know, it's, it's survived on the edge of Dunmar for a few hundred years.
DM: At least in theory the, um, you know, the
DM: Shakun Mystai cult does, does protect them.
DM: Um,
DM: you know, it's never felt l- it's never felt, I mean,
DM: at least Delwath I guess would know this, like, people there don't feel like they're living on the edge of danger.
DM: Um-
Unknown: Uh, right
DM: ... and it's not some, it's not, you know, they feel safe there.
Kenzo: So just looking at the party again.
Kenzo: You know, the festival's not for another 10 days.
Kenzo: Uh, we should definitely make it back before the festival, but should we continue east more?
Kenzo: It seems like, uh, Akan and his friends will be fine.
DM: Yes.
Seeker: We haven't explored that more in that direction.
Unknown: So...
Delwath: Yes, we should continue east.
Seeker: How are we for, like, water?
Delwath: There might be things to learn there.
Seeker: I guess we can refill here. We're at literally an oasis.
Seeker: [laughs]
DM: There's wells at the oasis.
DM: You can, you can get more water.
DM: And if you, I mean, you would have left with, I assume, a decent amount of food, and you have Delwath's horse to carry stuff on, so, um.
Unknown: Unless you're-
DM: You know, as long as you have the horse, you're, you're pretty much fine for supplies.
Seeker: So first priority, track down some gigantic flightless birds, train them.
Unknown: Yes.
Seeker: Make some saddles.
Kenzo: I hate that line, "As long as you have the horse, you'll be fine."
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Oh, God.
Seeker: [laughs]
Kenzo: [laughs] I probably shouldn't have said that out loud for Tim, but...
DM: Oh, I choose my words carefully.
Wellby: [laughs]
Seeker: He's got that look, he does.
Delwath: I knew why he said that. I mean.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: Tim's doing the face. Tim's doing the face.
Seeker: [laughs]
DM: Hold on. I need to look something up for Mike.
Kenzo: No. You don't have to look things up.
Seeker: [laughs] Oh, no.
Seeker: I hate it when Tim does the face.
Wellby: Let me consult the disaster table.
Seeker: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Um.
Seeker: Ooh, nice oasis, Mike.
Delwath: Yeah. Y- I, I switched to the oasis, like,
Unknown: an hour ago. [laughs]
Kenzo: Was that an hour ago? I think we were closer, like, you leaned back so now you could see, see it.
Delwath: Yeah. I, I, I did lean back so you could see the water a bit more.
Seeker: Yeah.
Delwath: It's actually a, it's a, it's a river on the Ba- in the Bahop, and it's, it's not really an oasis, but it was the closest I could find.
Kenzo: All right. Should we, uh, shall we travel east then?
Wellby: Do it.
Kenzo: Yes. Are there tracks to follow?
Unknown: Are there lizard tracks?
DM: Oh, yeah. The lizard tracks are abundantly clear.
DM: Like, four giant lizards, like, running through the desert leave a trail that nobody could miss.
Seeker: Mm-hmm.
DM: Um.
Kenzo: All right. Are, are, are any of you skilled at tracking, by the way?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Ha, the elf.
Seeker: Naturally.
Kenzo: I, I, you know, I just nod at, um, at Seeker and, um,
Unknown: and Wellby.
Kenzo: You seen an elf before the, before, before the elf?
Seeker: Uh, probably not, right?
Unknown: I don't think so.
Wellby: Have I, Kim?
DM: Uh, you probably would have at some point in your tr- your wide travels.
DM: I mean, there are, um,
DM: uh ...
DM: Uh, but I don't think any else of you would have.
DM: Um ...
Seeker: I've heard tell of them.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: Read a story or two.
Wellby: I met a couple. I mean, not
Wellby: ... I don't count them among my close friends, but I've met a, met a handful.
Seeker: Hmm.
Kenzo: So w- we, are we, are we leaving?
Unknown: Are we now, like, heading east,
Unknown: following the tracks?
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: Uh, yes.
Seeker: But didn't we tell them that we were gonna stay until they came back?
DM: They, they all came back.
Delwath: Well, they came back. They came back and left already.
DM: And left.
Seeker: Oh, the whole... They all came back and then-
DM: They all came back. The young guy galloped off on the horses to warn-
Seeker: Everything's fine. Okay
DM: ... so everybody else, like, loaded up.
DM: You guys-
Seeker: All right
DM: ... refilled your water.
DM: Um,
DM: uh.
Seeker: So we'll follow the tracks.
DM: So the tracks, um, as you set out, the tracks, um, the tracks head along the, uh, this old trade road, right?
DM: So this is a, this is an ancient road that, that cut across the country of, of Dunmar before the Great War and before the-
Unknown: Ah, ancient road
DM: ... the Cataclysm. Um-
Kenzo: Did our old characters travel on this road, Tim?
Kenzo: Have we, have we, uh, have we been on this road before?
DM: Uh, yes, definitely.
DM: Um-
Unknown: Nice.
Wellby: Oh, sweet.
DM: Um, so...
Unknown: Um.
DM: Sorry, go ahead.
Kenzo: I was gonna say, a- as we walk, can we have a conversation, just, uh, as we go?
DM: Sure.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: Let me just do a tiny bit of description and then tell me-
Unknown: Okay
DM: ... what you wanna, what you wanna do as you're walking, if anybody wants to do anything in particular.
DM: Um, so,
DM: um,
DM: east of the oasis, the road is, is hardly traveled and it's not really much of a road anymore.
DM: So what, where you ca- you were following this road from when you met Alesh to the oasis, and it w- it's pretty well traveled there, so, you know, it's,
DM: you know, by horses and, and herds of sheep and things, so there's a clear track through the land.
DM: Here, it's clear nobody really goes east of the oasis, and so, um, you know, all you can really see besides the clear tracks of the lizards heading due east
DM: is, like, the occasional bit of stone or, like, um, some bit of edging.
DM: So this used to be a paved road, uh, with, like, nice edges and, like, big stone tiles and things like that, but these are mostly cracked and sort of, um, you
DM: know, thrown to pieces. The area to the north is, continues to be much greener and wetter with scrub and trees, um, while the area to the south continues to be,
DM: um, sort of bare rocks and heading into the sort of badlands, canyon lands.
DM: Uh, as you ride along, um, in the, in the mid-morning now, I guess, um,
DM: you know, the, the scene is very peaceful, if you could ignore the evidence before your eyes of these, uh, lizards
DM: coming out of, out of somewhere.
DM: There's flowers blooming, like, the ground is green from the winter rains.
DM: This would be prime grazing land, but you don't see anybody
DM: at all. Um, no clouds of dust, no nothing seems to be moving in the sun.
Seeker: Is the-
Unknown: So, um, um-
Seeker: ... transition of the type of
Seeker: landscape sharply made at the road they're on?
DM: It's, it's, it's not super sharp.
DM: It's, like, a few miles to the south is where it starts to transition, but the, the road does seem to be sort of the edge of the,
DM: of the sort of greener area.
Seeker: Hmm.
Kenzo: So, um, as we're walking, you know, uh, 'cause we're all, we're walking with the horse, right, as we go, traveling.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: So, uh, I, uh, just kind of looking over at Seeker,
Unknown: but, you know, loud enough... Oh, is Schwartz still there?
Wellby: I think he stepped away for a minute.
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: Okay. Well, we'll continue, and if Schwartz can't hear, you know, whatever.
Wellby: Yeah.
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: Seeker.
Seeker: Hmm.
Kenzo: And I, I say this loud enough in, uh, you know, kind of your shot of the elf.
Unknown: Seeker,
Unknown: what do you know about dreams?
Seeker: I'm very interested in dreams.
Seeker: I, uh,
Seeker: and I have some ideas about them.
Seeker: It's something that I would like to,
Seeker: to investigate.
Seeker: What I'm especially curious about are
Seeker: the connections between things, you might say.
Unknown: Hmm.
Seeker: As you've seen, I have this ability to create shapes in the world that
Seeker: channel the energy around us in useful ways.
Seeker: I think the way that I use this energy is a little bit different from how this elf does it or others do it.
Unknown: Hmm.
Seeker: There's a kind of...
Seeker: Not the kind of place that we're in, but a place where that power resides.
Seeker: And
Seeker: many have studied it, and many tap into that energy, as do I.
Seeker: I think that there's
Seeker: other places, too.
Seeker: This is the thing that seems less studied.
Seeker: [laughs] We're not-
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: ... the road. We're just, we're getting, like, super abstract now, so we're just, like, tripping over things.
Kenzo: Well, we're tracking as we're, as we're going, right, Tim?
Kenzo: So we're, we're just, you know...
DM: I'm just curious if anybody's, like who in particular is like paying attention.
Delwath: Uh, Delwath is tracking.
DM: Okay.
Wellby: Wellby too.
Kenzo: Um, [clears throat] wait, so sorry.
Kenzo: Say the last thing you just said again, uh, Eric?
Seeker: That's all just to say
Seeker: I have this question that I'm pursuing, which is how it all fits together.
Seeker: There's this place that we're in,
Seeker: there's the place that the magical energy comes from,
Seeker: and then sometimes a place that you go when you're asleep.
Seeker: And so my question is
Seeker: where are the portals between them that connect?
Seeker: Where are the intersections?
Seeker: What slices run through this world that show us the boundaries between them?
Unknown: Hmm.
Unknown: So
Kenzo: when we dream, you think we actually travel someplace, place else?
Seeker: Sometimes.
Seeker: Well, I can tell you about one thing that happened to me.
Seeker: It was really weird, this one thing that happened to me.
Seeker: Uh, my people,
Seeker: when we reach the cusp of adulthood,
Seeker: uh, carry out a ritual,
Seeker: and that is when I gave myself the name Seeker because what happened to me on this ritual, somewhat different than what happens to most.
Seeker: We travel deep down into the stone that we worship and shape.
Seeker: And,
Seeker: you know, my fellow classmates, my cohort, they all
Seeker: saw the deep inspiration in their studies for the architectural shaping of stone that I thought I also was gonna pursue in my adulthood, just like my
Seeker: parents did.
Seeker: But when I got down there and went deep into it,
Seeker: and deep into my own mind, I saw something somewhat different.
Seeker: It was a
Seeker: kind of
Seeker: floating place
Seeker: full of tiny points of light, which I gradually came to think might represent
Seeker: other minds.
Seeker: And this place,
Seeker: in the way that magical energy
Seeker: resides in a aboveness, even though it's not literally up above n- us, it has a kind of
Seeker: belowness.
Seeker: And more than that about their relation
Seeker: I can't say.
Seeker: But I've spent my life trying to find out.
Seeker: I also, you might be interested, [clears throat] have made some diagrams.
Seeker: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: Uh,
Seeker: the lines of magic force through the landscape, the strange shape of cataclysmic changes that seem to create these unnatural geological formations, I think there's a link between them, but I don't
Seeker: know what it is.
Unknown: Hmm.
Seeker: And the mystery cult in that town we were just in, they, as far as I have heard, have a connection to this magical dream world.
Seeker: And so perhaps there's a relationship between the pattern of lines of magical energy that converge on their temple, and the fact-
Unknown: Hmm
Seeker: ... that they can enter into and draw power from perhaps the world of dreams.
Seeker: Perhaps those things are all r- related.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: But we didn't really get a chance to talk to them while we were there though, so who knows?
Wellby: That it could be a doorway, you think?
Seeker: I'd love to go through that door if one such door exists.
Delwath: Have, have you heard the tales of the oasis in town?
DM: No, you haven't.
Seeker: Uh, nope.
Seeker: [laughs] W- what are the tales of the oasis?
Delwath: Hold on one second.
Delwath: Let me just ...
DM: Schwartz, I'll send you a message when you get a chance.
Wellby: Oh, thank you. Sorry.
Wellby: I'm making late night peanut butter and jellies.
Wellby: [laughs]
Seeker: Awesome.
Delwath: There's a
Delwath: ...
Delwath: There's the, um,
Delwath: there's a tale they tell in the village that if you spend a night
Delwath: at the edge of the oasis, waiting patiently, Shakun herself will come to you in a vision and show you one true thing about your future.
Seeker: Oh.
Unknown: Seeker,
Kenzo: the elf and I have been talking about dreams.
Seeker: Have you now?
Unknown: I wanna know more about these dreams.
Kenzo: This is part of why I'm here in this town.
Kenzo: Like you, I also am interested in this, in this, in, um, what's the name of the cult again?
Unknown: The, uh ...
Delwath: Shakun.
Unknown: The Shakun.
Seeker: Hmm.
Kenzo: It's, it's strange, these dreams.
Kenzo: I, I wonder if it has anything to do with what's happening here with these animals.
Unknown: I
Kenzo: ... The scene earlier when we first arrived into town,
Kenzo: I'd been there before. I'd seen it before.
Unknown: I'd dreamed it before.
Seeker: Really?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Do you have any idea why that might be?
Seeker: I wish that I did.
Wellby: Wait, say that again.
Wellby: When you came into town ... I, I just didn't hear what you said.
Kenzo: Oh, I just said, uh, I said when I, when I came to town, the scene outside the c- of town, I'd seen it before.
Kenzo: I dreamed it before, like I'd been there myself,
Unknown: even though it's my first time ever here.
Delwath: Speaking of places you've been before,
Delwath: it might be worth mentioning there's a,
Delwath: there's a ruin, um, a ruined
Delwath: city
Delwath: only a few days southeast of here.
Unknown: Yeah?
Unknown: Have you been there,
Unknown: Alf?
Delwath: I had occasion to-
Wellby: Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Wellby: I, I raise a hand.
Delwath: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: Yes, Wellby?
Wellby: Motioning you all to silence.
Wellby: Directing your attention
Wellby: off the side of the road,
Wellby: there's a handful of dead carcasses.
Wellby: Peccaries. I don't actually know what a peccary is, Tim.
DM: They're like, uh, s- small wild hogs.
DM: Like s- like small, though, not like a giant boar.
Wellby: But like scattering of them in the sense of not that one was killed and eaten, but some angry thing just murdered a bunch of them.
DM: Yeah, exactly. Like s- you can't...
DM: There's, there may be, uh, 100 yards ahead, so you don't see exactly how many, but five or six
DM: at least.
Unknown: Do we smell it?
Unknown: Dead things.
DM: Uh, uh, you're a little far away to smell them.
DM: It's just Wellby's good eyesight that-
Unknown: Mm
DM: ... spotted them this far away.
Wellby: I think I'll gesture for us to, like, move slowly, separate into two groups of two, and go forward cautiously.
Delwath: Yeah, the horse is gonna die now, isn't it?
DM: There doesn't seem to be anything moving.
DM: Uh, you, you spend a moment just kind of, you know, paying attention, and there's nothing moving ahead of you, just the dead bodies.
Unknown: Recently dead?
DM: Um,
DM: as you approach, uh, I guess make, um-
Unknown: Perception
DM: ... dead bodies, I'll say investigate.
DM: Investigation or medicine, your choice.
Unknown: Medicine.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: Oh, my D&D Beyond.
Unknown: Hold on a second.
Unknown: My medicine.
DM: Um.
Wellby: Sure thing.
Kenzo: Why is it not letting me make a medicine check?
Unknown: Oh, there it is.
Unknown: Investigation.
Kenzo: Let's all remember to talk about that ruined city later.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: Um, so, um,
DM: uh, Delwath, you, uh,
DM: um, notice, looking around, um, there's the...
DM: There's, like, of two of the tracks that you've been following sort of detour through this crowd, and there was, like, this...
DM: Seems like there's signs of a, of carnage, basically, of a couple giant lizards, like, just ripping through these.
DM: The, the creatures seem to be
DM: a, a day or two dead.
DM: It's hard to say exactly, but, you know, not a few hours and not weeks.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: So plausibly, they were killed by the same lizards.
DM: Yes. Plausibly, they would have been killed by the same lizards.
Delwath: You're smiling evilly, like something's gonna happen.
DM: Sometimes I just do that to keep you on your toes.
Delwath: And, um-
Wellby: [laughs]
Seeker: Have they got bite marks, kind of like the sheep did and other kind of bodily wound?
DM: They're... I mean, they're really torn to pieces, right?
DM: There's, like, uh, you know, entrails scattered about, but very little flesh left, um, on most of them.
DM: Uh, there's a couple that are just rotting that seem to be not, um,
DM: particularly eaten, but, you know, flung about almost, like something grabbed it by the neck and, like, threw it, uh, into the ground.
DM: They're, like, back broken, like, just kind of smashed.
DM: Looks very violent.
Kenzo: Killed for s- yeah, killed for sport, huh?
Kenzo: They look almost like they're killed for sport, I ask to the group.
Unknown: Could be.
Wellby: Yeah, could be.
Unknown: No, um, giant feathers, are there?
DM: No giant feathers.
Unknown: Damn.
Delwath: The tracks keep going on the other side?
DM: Yes.
Wellby: Onward.
DM: If any-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... if this is the same lizards, it w- it probably was based on the tracks.
DM: This was a detour, not a,
DM: a stop exactly.
Unknown: Onwards on the road?
Unknown: Yeah, let's continue.
Kenzo: Alf, tell us more about these, these ruins,
Unknown: city.
Delwath: I, I don't know much more than they exist, to be honest.
Unknown: Hmm.
Delwath: When I was here
Delwath: before, when I was there before, rather, let's just say
Delwath: I was... had other things on my mind and didn't take the time to explore a mysterious ruin.
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: When you were here before, before, or before?
Delwath: It was recently.
Delwath: Um, I,
Delwath: I came to this region, uh...
Delwath: When I arrived in this region from elsewhere,
Delwath: it was near this ruined city.
Unknown: Hmm.
Unknown: Elsewhere?
Unknown: Is this the city from before the Great War?
Delwath: That's a good question, Tim.
DM: I, I mean, you and I-
Delwath: But I-
Delwath: ... have no way of knowing.
Delwath: No, I mean, did-
DM: You weren't-
Delwath: But I have n- I guess I wasn't, I wasn't well enough traveled to have known.
DM: Before the war, you never traveled in Dunmar, so.
Delwath: I don't, I don't know. I never traveled this far south before the war.
DM: Hmm. [clears throat]
Wellby: Uh, how did you come directly...
Wellby: You said you came directly...
Wellby: How did you get there without coming from s- somewhere?
Kenzo: Yeah, I thought you might ask that.
Seeker: [laughs] A r- a reasonable- [laughs] ...
DM: question.
Kenzo: Kenza just starts, like, laughing hysterically.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: How long have you ever gone from one place to another?
Unknown: [laughs] Uh.
DM: Well, sometimes,
DM: uh,
Delwath: you spend time in, in
DM: a nightmare.
Delwath: Some of us have, at least.
Delwath: I wouldn't recommend it generally as a place to go.
Wellby: Like a dream?
DM: I don't know.
DM: It was just a place.
DM: Time didn't seem to pass.
DM: Bad things kept happening,
DM: the same ones over and over.
DM: What kind of bad things?
Delwath: Well, I spent a lot of time watching my comrades be murdered by Shimut's army.
DM: Did that really happen?
Delwath: That did really happen.
DM: And so you were seeing it again.
DM: Almost reliving it.
Wellby: Were you reliving it?
DM: You know, it's, it's hard to know.
Delwath: Hmm. It was, it was a, it was an odd place, almost like a shadow of this world.
DM: Vast and shadowy.
DM: Nothing quite real.
Delwath: I think nightmare may be the best term I can think of.
DM: Hmm.
DM: As you continue
DM: talking through the day, as you travel and track, um,
DM: it is, it is now getting towards evening.
DM: Um,
DM: and in the late afternoon sun, uh, you see ahead of you a gash in the world, almost as if,
DM: uh, like a giant sword or a, or a giant hand just pulled the earth apart.
DM: Um,
DM: this must be the canyon you saw from a distance.
DM: It's, it's just cuts through the landscape, not related to the geology of the world at all.
DM: Um,
DM: the road just kind of ends on the edge of this cliff, um,
DM: looking down, uh, hundreds of feet, um, into the down path talus slopes and, and into the drastic die bottom of this,
DM: just this cleft through the ground.
DM: And you feel,
DM: staring across this canyon, that there is something different about the world beyond, that this is,
DM: this is not just stepping,
DM: um, you know, this... On the other side of this canyon is not just, um,
DM: more of the same. It's, this is the true wilds.
DM: This is the cursed lands of the, of the Great War.
DM: This is, this is the Blasted Plains.
DM: And it's, uh,
DM: you know, staring across, contemplating this, it's, it's a,
DM: it's something, it's something different and new and, and more than you've,
DM: uh,
DM: something wilder than you've, than you've seen before in your travels.
DM: Um-
Seeker: D- Sorry, go ahead. Does it remind me of, um, that thing
DM: that I, that I found
DM: a long time ago?
Seeker: Um. With the volcano.
DM: [laughs] Trying to remember what you're referring to.
DM: [laughs] Um.
DM: Uh, oh, no, no, it doesn't remind you of that.
Seeker: I'm, I'm just curious to know if I can
Seeker: sense anything about the, the ley line patterns in this area.
DM: Ah, I remember what you're talking about now.
DM: Um,
DM: uh.
Kenzo: Willis doesn't like the change in music.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: I'm fine. Ca- I mean, is the, is crossing the canyon feasible?
Delwath: Like, is it, are we coming to the edge of it and we have to go down?
DM: Or is... Like, I'm just trying to picture it.
DM: Um,
DM: uh, yes, you, well, it, it extends, um, north-south
DM: s- across your path.
DM: Um, it certainly looks like it, it might be, you know, it's, it's not a straight drop 800 feet down.
DM: Right. So you could probably descend with some care.
DM: Um,
DM: the land to the south, uh,
DM: you know, if you were to go along the edge, um, seems like it quickly turns into this, you know, chaotic, uh, twisted tunnels of canyons and badlands.
DM: To the north is still the same, um, kind of grasslands, rolling hills, dry plains.
DM: It's not obvious exactly how far north the canyon extends.
Delwath: And it's too wide to, like,
DM: throw a rope across or something? Yeah, yeah, it's like a mile wide.
DM: W- we're the-
Kenzo: I feel like it's kind of like Eric's background.
DM: Yeah.
DM: [laughs] Uh, yeah, it is, it is kind of like that, except not maybe quite so pretty.
Seeker: More ominous.
DM: Mm.
Unknown: We're, we're not-
Seeker: Do the li- lizard tracks come up out of it?
DM: The lizard tracks come up out of it.
DM: You also see... Well,
DM: um, you see looking around here as well, um, there are, there's some, uh, sort of on the side north of the road, there's like
DM: the, the remains, just like foundations, just stones kind of laid out in a, in the, the pattern of, of a ruins of like a way station or, or something.
DM: Um,
DM: you know, some kind of,
DM: uh,
DM: some sort of ruined, um,
DM: inn or, or roadhouse or something like that.
DM: Um,
DM: you know,
DM: not, not recent.
DM: Something that is, that is a few hundred years old at least, right?
DM: There's nothing that... There's no walls or, or roofs or anything that remains standing.
Unknown: I think if
Delwath: we can keep tracking the lizards,
Delwath: this is a lead.
Seeker: We should keep go- going.
DM: We-
Seeker: What time of day is it?
DM: Um, close to evening.
Seeker: Mm.
DM: I'd say it's, uh, it's an hour before sunset maybe.
Seeker: Let's stay in this inn. It looks nice.
Unknown: Yep.
Seeker: [laughs]
Unknown: Wait, where's the inn? Sorry, I missed something.
Seeker: No, no, it's like a pile of rocks.
Seeker: It's like a-
Unknown: Oh, okay, okay.
DM: It's not... It, it's a, it's a-
Seeker: It's a ruin of an inn
Delwath: ... it's like a couple of stones that used to be an inn.
Seeker: Ah, right.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Um,
Seeker: and
Seeker: I don't sense magical lines of force crossing through.
Seeker: It would be interesting to know if there was any
Seeker: magic in operation around here.
Seeker: Should we, uh... It's gonna be dark soon.
Unknown: I-
Seeker: Mm-hmm
Kenzo: ... I don't know about you, you fellows, but, um, not eager to spend the evening across that way.
DM: Agreed.
Kenzo: What if we, um, make camp here?
Seeker: Mm.
Kenzo: We can maybe investigate the, the canyon a little bit and try to find a good path across for the morning.
Seeker: Yep.
Delwath: I think that's sensible.
Delwath: I did spend two nights in the, in the Blasted Lands a few months ago, but
Unknown: no ill befell me.
Seeker: Mm.
Delwath: But that's not to say we should rush in the, in there.
Seeker: Seems like the, a good place to set out in the morning.
Kenzo: Tim, uh, if we've got like an hour before sunset, um-
DM: Yep.
Kenzo: Oh, go ahead. Were you gonna say something, Tim?
DM: Nope.
Kenzo: Um, sh- if we plan to make camp here, should we, uh, investigate the chasm a little bit and try to find a good route across-
Seeker: Yeah
Kenzo: ... before, before it gets dark so we know what to do in the morning?
Seeker: And let's see if the tracks...
Delwath: I mean, it would be good to see if the tracks come out the other side.
Kenzo: Yeah. Tim, how wide is the canyon again?
Unknown: You said it was, it was like a mile?
DM: It's, it's wide. It's like a mile across.
Kenzo: All right. So I mean, we could reasonably like get down there, kind of investigate, and then, and then-
DM: [sneezes]
Kenzo: ... get back, climb back up before it gets dark.
DM: Uh, yeah, if you wanna try to do that.
DM: Um.
Unknown: Yes.
Unknown: I'm gonna use-
DM: Uh, okay, so, um-
Seeker: I wanna use, um,
Seeker: stone sense,
Seeker: uh, while we're doing, while we're climbing down.
Seeker: I guess it's only for 10 minutes, but while we're descending.
DM: Okay. I gotta remind myself of...
DM: Hold on one sec here.
Unknown: Where's the horse?
Delwath: Yeah, I was just thinking about that. I think we leave the horse in the ruins of the inn.
Delwath: I don't think we take it into the...
Kenzo: Maybe someone should stay here with the horse.
Seeker: [laughs]
Seeker: What could possibly go wrong?
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: I don't know. I think either we, we
Delwath: leave it to chance or bring it with us, but I,
Delwath: I guess, I mean, presumably if we're gonna continue onward,
Delwath: we would expect to, to have to be able to bring...
Delwath: to find a path down that the horse can, can travel.
Seeker: That's true. That's true.
Unknown: So let's just, let's just take it.
Kenzo: Let's bring the horse. Let's bring the horse.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Uh, okay. Um, who's leading the way?
Kenzo: Who's our... I guess, is it, uh, has it been the elf that's kind of the lead tracker?
DM: Yeah, I'll lead.
Unknown: All right.
Seeker: Oh, we're tracking
DM: Make a survival.
Seeker: Yeah.
DM: Give me a survival check.
Unknown: Great.
Seeker: Everybody?
DM: No, just Delwath.
Unknown: 19.
DM: Okay. So you, you begin picking your way down the cliff, and, and, um, you know, it's, the descent is not too bad for the first 400 feet or so.
DM: It, um, you know, you manage to, to sort of navigate, um, a path and, and sort of pick your way down the slope.
DM: It's, it's steep and you have to be careful, um, uh, but it's not a sheer cliff.
DM: Uh,
DM: and, you know, probably takes you, you know, oh,
DM: 15, 20 minutes to kind of pick your way slowly down with the horse.
DM: Um-
Unknown: Mm-hmm
DM: ... it's, as you start to pick your way down, it's, it's abundantly clear how, um, you know, especially to Seeker, but really to all of you, how sort of the wrongness
DM: of this canyon. It's not, it's not like a canyon carved by s- you know, the action of water.
DM: You don't see neat sedimentary layers in the rocks.
DM: There's like sharp rocks that jut out in all directions.
DM: Um, you know, there's, there's boulders that are sort of resting on ledges that are, that are cracked in half, just clean sheared down the middle, like somebody just sliced a bold-
DM: sliced through the boulder.
DM: Um, you know, as you begin to sort of, sort of pick your way down as well, um, you know, the rock- Is, is not,
DM: it's not sandstone.
DM: It's not what you'd sort of expect.
Seeker: Mm-hmm.
DM: And, you know, after heading down about 400 feet, um, you come to an area where there seems to be a layer of just like hard basalt or some sort of igneous rock,
DM: um, that drops maybe 100 feet in a, in a cliff to a, uh, to a talus slope below it.
DM: Um, and you sort of, you sort of pick your way along, um, but it's not,
DM: it's not clear that there's an easy way
DM: past this basalt layer without finding a way down the cliff.
Seeker: So there's a phenomenon where, uh, in layers of basalt, a, uh, a void is made by, uh, liquid passing through, which is then later filled by
Seeker: some, uh, mineral deposit that forms a beautiful crystalline structure, uh, which can come in any of a range of colors.
Seeker: It's sometimes known as beryllium or beryl.
DM: [laughs]
Seeker: I'm just explaining all of this as we pass by.
Unknown: And do you, uh, see my note?
DM: Uh,
DM: yes.
DM: Um...
Seeker: What do you all think explains the phenomenon here?
Kenzo: What's going on? What happened here?
Seeker: It's, uh, this is clearly not, uh, a natural erosion process.
Seeker: That much, that much seems obvious.
DM: Um, so it's now maybe,
DM: uh,
DM: 40 minutes till sunset.
DM: The sun is sort of just touching the horizon, and you're at the top of 100-foot cliff.
Seeker: We're at the top of it? Oh.
Wellby: Let's head back up and make camp.
Seeker: Sounds good.
Unknown: I mean, would it be...
Delwath: That's probably the, the right thing to do, but would it be possible to...
Delwath: I mean, is there something just to like tie a rope on?
Unknown: I mean, what's the...
Seeker: Make camp here?
DM: I mean-
Delwath: To just rappel down the side of the cliff.
DM: Yeah, you could probably, um...
DM: You know, there's like sharp rocks and stuff jutting around.
DM: There's not, you know, a convenient tree or anything.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Um.
Seeker: So what's at the bottom of the cliff?
DM: The bottom of this cliff seems to be like a, like a talus slope that leads down to the bottom of the canyon.
DM: Like loose, loose rock.
Delwath: How did the lizards get down this?
Wellby: Yeah.
Seeker: Or up, I suppose.
DM: Um, so the lizard tracks sort of stop at the top of the cliff.
DM: You can't really track anything on the cliff.
DM: Um, but I guess they climbed.
DM: It's not, you know, a completely sh- it's not like a smooth glass face, right?
DM: Like, the rock is sort of cracked and, um,
DM: you know, if you were,
DM: if you were skilled at climbing, as lizards often are-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... it wouldn't be that bad of an ascent.
Kenzo: Hm. Can we track the lizards from here, Alf?
Delwath: I've totally lost the trail, Tim, or can I try and find it again?
DM: Uh, you find the trail.
DM: Go... I mean, you can... You've been following the trail down through this sort of rubble.
Unknown: Ah.
DM: Once it goes off the cliff-
Unknown: Hits the cliff
DM: ... there's no way you... There's nothing to track.
DM: It's just a bare surface, right?
DM: There's no... Doesn't, nothing leaves trail on ba- bare rock, so.
Kenzo: So in the morning, I mean, we can
Kenzo: s- try to pick up the trail at the bottom of the cliff, yeah?
Seeker: Yeah.
Delwath: We're not gonna be able to get the horse down this, though.
Seeker: Hm.
Seeker: Oh, um, can I...
Seeker: Does, does my stone sense reveal anything?
Seeker: I'm, like, picking up a flat piece of basalt and sketching a glowing spiraling pattern on it and holding it up in front of me as I slowly turn around.
DM: [coughs]
Seeker: Hm.
Seeker: I feel like we should go back up and make camp.
Seeker: I'm, I'm getting interested in something, staring into the basalt cliff face.
Seeker: Uh,
Seeker: well, that's very interesting.
Seeker: I wonder what that is.
DM: Uh, make an intelligence check.
Seeker: Oh, wait, did that work?
DM: I didn't see anything.
Seeker: Oh, I have to do it again.
Unknown: Yes.
Wellby: Nice.
Seeker: [laughs]
Seeker: 10.
Seeker: Ah, indeed.
DM: [laughs]
Seeker: That phenomenon I mentioned earlier,
Seeker: uh, there's one of them just over here.
Seeker: It's unfortunately, uh, not visible, uh, to your eyes because it's buried deep in, in the, in the stone, but, uh, it is a, what appears to be a large
Seeker: and beautifully formed deposit of beryllium.
Unknown: Hm.
DM: Alas.
Seeker: We can't get at it easily now.
Seeker: Maybe in the morning.
Unknown: Is it unusual for this to be here?
Seeker: Uh, Tim?
Wellby: Uh.
Seeker: No? That's like a natural phenomenon of the cooling, uh, essentially the, um, the cooling processes of molten rock within the earth, uh, proceed at
Seeker: different rates over time, you see, and that affects the granularity of the crystal structures.
Seeker: Perhaps we should get back to camp.
Seeker: [laughs]
Wellby: Yeah.
Kenzo: Let's continue the, let's continue this lecture over the fire.
Unknown: How about that?
Seeker: Okay.
Unknown: So we
Kenzo: go back up to where the, uh, the little bit of rubble was and we set up camp, yeah?
Seeker: Yep.
Wellby: I think we shouldn't make a fire tonight, though.
Wellby: Too visible here.
Seeker: Yes.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: And, uh, and we should set watches like before.
Wellby: What are we gonna do with this horse tomorrow?
Seeker: Hmm.
Unknown: Hmm.
DM: I send you a message, Schwartz.
Seeker: Uh, uh, I will...
Wellby: Oh, interesting.
Wellby: Interesting. As we start to, you know, we're unrolling sleeping bags or, I don't know, whatever adventurers carry, and, um,
Wellby: I spot something out of the corner of my eye and say, "Whoa, there's something over here.
Wellby: We're not the first people to pass through these way, this way."
Wellby: And I head back, uh, having spotted something and, uh, investigate it.
Wellby: Tim, what's-
DM: Uh, sure.
DM: Give me a perception check.
Unknown: That's pretty perceptive.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Mm-hmm, mm-hmm. Strong.
Wellby: Someone passed through here deliberately trying to cover their tracks.
Wellby: Hmm. They did a pretty good job of, uh,
Wellby: hiding. I can't tell how many there were even here.
Seeker: Hmm.
Seeker: Humans?
Wellby: There's a fire ring, so,
Wellby: you know, humans, humanoids.
Seeker: Wow.
Wellby: No animals, no horses.
Wellby: Probably just one human, I think.
Unknown: How long ago?
Seeker: Recently.
Unknown: Recently?
Seeker: Hmm.
DM: Uh, hold on.
Wellby: Wellby pauses, deep in thought.
Wellby: Uh, no, not in the last few days.
Seeker: Hmm.
Wellby: Can't have been, you know, ages and ages ago, but-
Unknown: Sure
Wellby: ... not in the last few days.
Unknown: Somebody made camp here.
Wellby: Somebody made camp here, but more interesting to me, they tried to cover their traces.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Hmm. Why would they do that?
Seeker: Perhaps they knew that someone else was after them.
Unknown: Several days ago?
Wellby: At least.
Unknown: Before the hyenas.
Seeker: Mm-hmm.
Seeker: Before the hyenas.
Wellby: Interesting.
Seeker: Hmm.
Wellby: Definitely before the hyenas.
Wellby: This is the person we should be tracking.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Can we find their trail?
Wellby: It's hard to say. I mean, it could have been weeks ago that they came through here.
Wellby: I think we keep looking for signs on the road tomorrow.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: And we all get a fitful, nice rest.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Seeker: Right, Tim?
DM: Yeah, you all, um,
DM: s- uh, surprisingly-
Delwath: Delwath will again volunteer to take two watches.
Seeker: Mm-hmm.
DM: Okay. It's, it's,
DM: it's difficult sleeping, you know, out here.
DM: It's, it's, it's quiet.
DM: Um,
DM: uh, it's
DM: almost too quiet, um, after the, you know, the
DM: chaos of the past night.
DM: And you can still sort of feel the presence of, of something on the other side of the canyon.
DM: But you do manage to sleep uninterrupted.
Kenzo: Ugh, can't wait to get back to the city myself.
Seeker: You don't love the rocks out here?
Seeker: They're beautiful. Spectacular place,
Seeker: if a little unnatural.
Unknown: I'm a city boy.
Seeker: Hmm.
Unknown: I don't mind the nature, but
Kenzo: hopefully we figure out what's going on out here soon.
Wellby: It'll be good to get back in time for the festival, for sure.
Kenzo: Wellby, is, uh, Wellby and the elf, are we, uh, are we able to track whoever was here before?
Wellby: It's gonna be, uh-
DM: This is the next morning
Wellby: ... hard.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: It's the morning.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: you notice that, um, Delwath kind of packs his armor away.
Delwath: Uh, hold on a second. Wait one second.
Seeker: Braveheart.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: uh, you notice, um, Delwath, he sort of, when he wakes up and is sort of getting organized for the day, um,
Delwath: he kinda glances around, um,
Delwath: after a minute, uh, and then kind of smiles a little bit and, and just, and packs his armor away on the horse Were you,
Unknown: uh, were you wearing armor before?
DM: You've been wearing chain mail.
Unknown: Hmm.
DM: Oh, if you're getting ready to climb?
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: no. I've, uh,
Unknown: um...
Unknown: I've found a better way.
Seeker: A better way?
Unknown: Can, can the horse go?
DM: Uh, not...
DM: A better way to protect myself.
Delwath: This is very, he kind of holds up the armor, it's
Delwath: a bit clunky and visible.
Seeker: Hmm.
Unknown: Hmm.
DM: So what are you doing with the horse?
DM: Are you just gonna leave it tied up?
Unknown: Is there, is there any way-
Seeker: I think so
Kenzo: ... is there any way to get across with the horse?
Kenzo: Is there any path for the horse?
DM: You could go north until you find the end of the canyon.
Seeker: That would not be unreasonable.
Unknown: How far?
Wellby: Can we rappel a horse down?
Delwath: No, but I wanna see what's down there.
Delwath: I mean, you're right, it wouldn't be unreasonable, but...
Seeker: Hmm.
Wellby: Uh, what do we need the horse for again?
Kenzo: It's got all of our food and provisions.
Wellby: Oh.
Delwath: I mean, that's the main thing it d- it has, but...
Wellby: Hmm.
Kenzo: If we were to try to get to the edge of the canyon, how far would we have to go, Tim?
DM: Uh, if you tried to go north, you don't know.
DM: You can't, you can't see,
DM: uh, you know, i- as far as you...
DM: It's, you know, it's
DM: at least as far as you can see looking at the edge of the canyon, it extends as far as you can see.
DM: So it, so miles for sure.
Unknown: Miles.
DM: Whether it's 50, whether it's 10 miles or 15 miles or 30 miles, you can't really tell.
Seeker: Yeah.
DM: But you're not, you're not talking about, you know,
DM: a few hundred yards or even just a mile.
Unknown: Got a bad feeling about this.
Delwath: I, I think we should go into the canyon.
DM: I think we-
Wellby: Can I have the horse or, or let it go?
Delwath: I would let it go.
Delwath: I, we, let's take, let's take what we can carry-
Wellby: Yep
DM: ... and, and let it go.
Unknown: Let it go. Why not tie it here?
Delwath: If a wizard comes, I am hoping it can run to safety.
Seeker: Can I use mold earth
Seeker: to make persistent structures
Seeker: that I walk away from?
Seeker: Let's see.
DM: Yeah, it just excavates earth for you.
DM: You can then pack it into whatever, you know,
DM: the, the, sh- it, it doesn't go back, the, like, you dig a [meows] five foot cube out, you move the earth somewhere,
DM: and that's permanent.
DM: It doesn't, like-
Seeker: Mm-hmm
Delwath: ... go back into the ground or anything.
Seeker: Oh, but I can only do two of those at once, and then,
Seeker: yeah.
DM: No, you can dig qui-
Seeker: Can you, like-
DM: You can actually dig very efficiently with mold earth.
DM: You can, technically speaking, you can excavate one five foot cube per six seconds.
Seeker: [coughs] It's like Minecraft or some shit.
DM: Yeah, basically it is.
Seeker: All right, well, I, I can, um, make an enclosure for our supplies
Seeker: that at least has, like, some walls and a-
Wellby: Ooh, interesting
Seeker: ... doorway, so it's less likely to get random creatures.
Kenzo: Oh, you're gonna make an enclosure for the horse.
Seeker: Well, yeah, that's what I'm saying, for the horse and the supplies and stuff, where they're less likely to get randomly attacked by wandering giant flightless birds or whatever.
Delwath: I mean, I guess if you make a barn,
Unknown: effectively.
Seeker: The hinged doors are more difficult, but-
DM: Hinged doors and a roof might be a little tricky.
Wellby: Yes.
DM: The walls would be easy, just packed earth walls.
Seeker: Yeah. Yeah.
Unknown: Squeezed.
Delwath: Yeah. I mean, we could make, like, a packed earth wall barn, and then weave the,
DM: um-
Seeker: Yeah
Unknown: I love this idea.
Seeker: Yeah.
Kenzo: And then we can, then you can do the same thing, the remove a wall at, at the end when we come back, right?
DM: Oh, yeah, easily.
Seeker: That's interesting. I don't need a door.
DM: You can make it with no doors.
DM: Why do you need a door?
Unknown: Yeah, just wall it off.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: I feel a little, like, a twinge of, like, the shameful glances of my, of my parents over my shoulder as I construct something that does not
Seeker: have the beautiful soaring elegance of stone arches and domes.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: And instead is actually just a dirt, uh, box containing a horse, but nonetheless, it is a useful box.
DM: [laughs]
DM: So, yes, that you can do quite, quite quickly.
Seeker: Okay.
DM: It probably only takes you a couple minutes to, to dig that out with-
Seeker: Mm-hmm
DM: ... with mold earth, 'cause this, this is all just sort of loose dirt.
Seeker: Mm-hmm.
DM: So it's very easy to shape.
DM: Um, so once you've boxed in the horde, horse and the supplies, um-
Seeker: [laughs] Thanks, Kong
DM: ... you-
Seeker: I, I actually draw a little picture of it in the dirt before doing it, and the picture begins to glow, and then I expand it
Seeker: and gesture-
DM: As your, just like-
Seeker: ... over there
DM: ... dirt starts flying up
Seeker: ... it just raises it. Yeah.
DM: Um-
Unknown: That's dope. Cool.
DM: Nice.
DM: Okay, so now you're gonna head off down the cliff.
Unknown: Yep.
DM: Cool.
Kenzo: We should take bets, uh, about what's gonna happen to this horse.
Seeker: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs] I leave, like, a-
DM: I think it's literally in the chat
Delwath: The horse is still gonna be there
Seeker: ... there's at least one breathing hole and some water for the horse, it says.
Unknown: Well, no, it's, it's, it's, it's, it's-
Wellby: Well, there's no roof
Unknown: ... it's open air.
Seeker: Oh, okay. Right. Right. Right.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: It's four walls. Yeah.
Kenzo: Who thinks the horse is still gonna be there when we get back?
DM: Do you think we can bring some water?
Wellby: Uh, not me.
Kenzo: I'm gonna vote plus one, uh, horse lives.
Seeker: I'm all in on horse lives.
Seeker: [laughs]
DM: I'm betting zero chance.
DM: Horse lives matter.
Delwath: I'm on, I'm on zero chance horse lives.
Wellby: I, uh, none, zero.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: We're never coming back this way.
Unknown: Horse badly wounded?
DM: [laughs]
Wellby: Oh, no. Dead.
Delwath: Oh, wait. I was supposed to say that to everybody.
Unknown: Sorry.
Wellby: It looks like it's-
DM: But Akan, Mike said, said that privately.
Wellby: Making a grave for the horse will be very efficient for Seeker.
DM: Right.
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: That's true.
DM: Um-
Unknown: Making a what?
Wellby: [laughs]
Delwath: Delwath is, like, saying goodbye to the horse.
Delwath: And like, "This was... It was nice knowing you.
Delwath: Like, you were a good horse.
Delwath: I'm sorry that you had to die."
Delwath: Well, not quite, but like, you know.
Delwath: And I'll take whatever supplies we can reasonably carry.
Unknown: I mean, mostly water.
Unknown: Yeah, anything that we can carry.
DM: You can easily carry, like...
DM: I mean, all of you are puny weaklings,
DM: but you can carry easily, like, two or three days of food and water without a, without a problem.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: But if, but if you're gone from the hor- if you're gone from this camp for more than three days, it'll start to be an issue.
Kenzo: Oh, shit, but if we walled up the horse, does the horse have, like, water and stuff to, like, eat or if we're gone for a few days, is the horse gonna die inside the box?
Seeker: The interior is really actually elegantly constructed with a trough and, like, an area for it to poop and stuff.
Unknown: It's, it's actually-
Delwath: Although, it's presumably been surviving on, like, grazing.
DM: Yeah. I mean, you can make a pretty...
DM: You could enclose a fairly large area, right?
DM: You could have a-
Unknown: There you go
DM: ... grazing field in there.
Delwath: Have some, like, grass blocks.
Unknown: I just make sure that there are-
Unknown: Yeah, find a grassy place.
DM: Yes
Seeker: ... there aren't just inside the box, but it's-
Delwath: And we can give it some water. I mean, we have enough water.
Delwath: We filled up at the oasis. We would have enough water.
DM: Yeah, you have lots of water on the horse.
DM: Um.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: All right.
Kenzo: The horse will be fine. [laughs]
DM: The horse will probably, if it's not d- if, if you guys aren't back in three days and you all start dying of thirst, the horse will probably also be dying of thirst.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: Right.
DM: But you and the horse all have about three days of water.
Unknown: Let's go jump down a cliff.
Unknown: All right.
Unknown: Perfect.
Unknown: Yeah. Ready.
DM: Okay, so you make your way back down to the basalt outcropping,
DM: and what exactly do you wanna do?
Unknown: Uh, who's got rope?
Unknown: I got 50 feet of rope.
Wellby: I got rope.
Unknown: Same.
Seeker: So, um, how, how far down is it?
Unknown: 100 feet?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: I mean, can we,
Unknown: uh...
Unknown: You said it's not, like, um,
Delwath: a sheer cliff, right? Like, if we tie some rope, go down 50 feet, tie some, you know,
Unknown: drive a
Delwath: piece of metal or something into the, um-
DM: Do any of you have iron spikes?
Unknown: I have a crowbar.
Wellby: I have one hook.
Seeker: I have an ability to shape stone.
Unknown: I could, like, um-
Kenzo: Dude, I've got adventuring gear. Come on.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: The adventuring gear is perfect for this moment.
DM: Yeah. If, if, if you leave the r- I mean, if you're willing to leave the ropes behind,
DM: it would not be that big a dis- it would not be that difficult a descent.
DM: The only tricky thing is if somebody's trying to detach the rope from, and come down following the rope.
Wellby: Can Seeker use shape stone and just, like, make a ladder in the cliff?
Unknown: We discussed this last time.
DM: No, it d- we discussed it last time. It doesn't let you actually shape stone.
DM: It only lets you excavate loose rock or dirt.
Wellby: So it's more of a move dirt than shape stone?
Unknown: It's kind of a shovel, but like-
DM: It's, it's technically called mold, it's technically called mold earth.
Wellby: Ah.
DM: Um,
DM: yeah, there is a, a much higher level spell that lets you
DM: do exactly that, shape,
DM: shape stone.
Unknown: Mm.
Wellby: I'll be back in a minute.
Wellby: Roll for me if you need to.
Wellby: I'm just gonna do whatever is prudent.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: so we climb down the...
Delwath: I mean, I don't think we need to go back for our rope.
Unknown: We leave it here because-
Seeker: Well, if we leave the rope, we can... And then we'll be able to get back up from this, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: And it'll be totally obvious to the person who's actually following us that we came this way.
Kenzo: There's somebody fo- I thought we were following somebody else.
Delwath: I'm just being skeptical that we're by ourselves in the creepy land of-
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: ... whatever.
Kenzo: Well, I think if somebody wanted to follow us, I think it would be pretty obvious.
Unknown: I don't think we've been, like-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... you know, sneaky, you know?
Unknown: So.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Uh, yeah. So, um, so navigating, navigating down, so you, you, you know, uh,
DM: tie the rope off at the top, um, pretty securely.
DM: You know, drive your, use your crowbar to, like, you know,
DM: drive a wedge or something.
DM: Na- and nail in a few iron spikes or whatever and, and it's pretty solidly attached there it seems.
DM: Um,
DM: you know, it, it seems like it would be, uh,
DM: quite easy to get down.
DM: Um,
DM: it's, it's still a, it's still a long climb.
DM: but it's not, it's not hard, but I'm still gonna make you roll an athletics check.
Unknown: All of us?
DM: All of you, yeah.
Delwath: Athletics. I'm not gonna succeed on the athletics check.
Kenzo: Oh, athletics. I thought this would be, like, acrobatics.
Unknown: No.
DM: It's just ath- I mean, athletics is, is strength, right?
DM: It's-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... climbing down a rope is not.
Unknown: I rolled a 20 and got a 19.
DM: Uh.
Unknown: Oh, 11.
DM: 11, yep.
DM: Uh, do we need to roll for-
Unknown: Wellby?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Here, I can roll for him.
DM: 17. Okay, he's fine.
Unknown: Nice. Nice.
DM: Um,
DM: yeah, okay. You all, you all make it down without a, without a problem.
DM: It's, it's tiring. It's hard work.
DM: Uh, you know, carefully down the-
Delwath: Wait, do we all have minus one strengths?
Unknown: We're awesome. [laughs]
DM: You all have, you all have minus one strength.
Unknown: Whoops.
DM: Hence the you're all a bunch of weaklings.
Unknown: Wow.
DM: You have other skills.
Delwath: We are the s- strongest group of adventurers ever.
DM: Yeah. Um- Fortunately, you have a horse.
DM: Um-
Unknown: Who's dead.
Seeker: Horse in a box?
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: [laughs] I mean, we built a grave for it.
DM: Right.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: So, so as you get to the bottom, um,
DM: the-
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: ... uh, you know, the, the bottom of the canyon, um, is, is mostly all this sort of, like, loose, loose gravel and, um, you know, this,
DM: this sort of like the e- the edge of this talus slope, right?
DM: This, like, sort of loose rubble and stuff at the bottom of the cliff.
DM: Um, and
DM: it's very, very dry, and dusty, and hot even though it's not that late in the day.
DM: Um...
Delwath: Can we pick up the wizard trail at all?
DM: Uh, yeah, make a survival check.
Unknown: You all do that?
Delwath: I can, I'm pretty good at survival.
DM: No, just Delwath.
Delwath: I have a plus three. I don't know if anybody else is better.
Unknown: I have a plus three.
DM: Uh, okay.
DM: So y- yes, you can, um, you can see there's actually a number of tracks that seem to crisscross at the bottom here.
DM: Um, you know,
DM: s- some, the lizard tracks, uh, you do pick up again.
DM: Um,
DM: they seem to be heading towards the other side of the canyon.
DM: Um, you also... Kenzo, you also notice, um,
DM: hyena tracks, the, the tracks of the giant hyenas that seem to be heading south from here.
Unknown: Whoa.
Unknown: Weird.
DM: And there's other tracks-
Unknown: South
DM: ... sort of crisscrossing across, like some muddled that are hard to tell what they are.
DM: Some, uh,
DM: you know, like, uh, you know, a little bit of a claw scratch or something that could've been, you know, was made by some sort of animal.
DM: But it's, it seems like there's been a number of, of animals, um, crisscrossing the ground at the bottom here, and all, all of the tracks
DM: o- on the eastern side of the canyon converge on this one slope that is, this one sort of...
DM: So there's a, uh,
DM: how to describe this?
DM: Uh, in the, in the far side of the canyon you can see now that you're at the bottom, there's almost like a, uh, like a little slot canyon that sticks east and extends into the canyon
DM: wall, and then sort of gradually slopes upward.
DM: Um, and judging by the position, you would think that this would now connect with, if the, if you just drew a straight line on the road, almost like the area where the road was collapsed more and
DM: more gently so it provides, like, a slope going up.
DM: And all the tracks seem to be converging upon there.
Unknown: Let's go check it out.
DM: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: The hyenas were here.
Unknown: Incredible.
Unknown: Ah, interesting.
Unknown: We're getting close.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So as you head
DM: across the canyon and up the road,
DM: uh, beyond the canyon, um,
DM: the land is rough and torn,
DM: and what was... You can still see bits of the old trade road, but it's hardly detectable.
DM: And what was a formerly sort of straight and true road, even east of, of Gomat, um, is now
DM: crossed by occasional fallen rock or piles of loose debris.
DM: Um,
DM: the, the land itself is cracked, uh, and there's, you know, every now and then you'll see a, you know, another small, like, sort of gaping fissure like this, this
DM: canyon in, in miniature.
DM: And, uh, just any travel here, even along the road, is a, is a slow, hard process as you pick your way through this battered landscape.
DM: Um, in the distance maybe, um, three or four miles away, um, you can see,
DM: uh, a couple small, short towers, maybe two or three stories, um, ha- tall, um, standing, marking some
DM: old ruin, or fort, or something like that along the road.
Kenzo: Towers, three of them?
DM: Two, two towers, like a, like next to each other, like a gatehouse type thing.
Unknown: How tall?
DM: Maybe three stories tall.
DM: They're lacking roofs.
DM: They seem to be...
DM: From this distance it's hard to tell much more about them.
DM: It's several miles away.
DM: You just see, like, little,
DM: you know, little specks on the, on the horizon.
Unknown: Hm.
Unknown: Should we head there?
Unknown: Yep.
Unknown: Yeah, let's investigate the, uh,
Unknown: this gatehouse.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So as you begin,
DM: um, as you begin to head, um, towards this, this towers, uh,
DM: it's increasingly obvious that, that something seems,
DM: something seems wrong.
DM: Just past the canyon you see, um, a swarm of scorpions that are, um,
DM: just regular scorpions, like not big at all.
DM: Like, you know, small scorpions swarming across some sort of dead animal, just, like, using their claws to kind of rip into pieces of this, um, this
DM: creature's flesh.
DM: Um,
DM: you know, as you continue to walk you notice that, um,
DM: there are,
DM: you know, ants and small biting insects that are constantly seem to be harassing,
DM: almost intentionally seem like they're harassing you.
DM: Like, swarming up your legs, and you're stopping, not only dodging the, um,
DM: not only, you know, make, picking your way around the landscape but, like, you know, brushing these bugs off.
DM: Um...
Seeker: Wait, wait, wait, wait. I brought bug spray.
Seeker: I have, I have some...
Seeker: [laughs] I do literally have-
DM: Yes, you did.
Unknown: I do literally have-
Seeker: Insect repellent salve
Unknown: Seeker.
Seeker: [laughs]
Unknown: Genius.
Seeker: You notice that I, I pause on the road and take out a, a tube of something that smells really bad.
Seeker: It's like this greasy-
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: ... material, and I'm, I'm swabbing it on my ankles where I've just been bit by an ant.
Unknown: Any more of that, Seeker?
Seeker: I'm, I'm willing to share.
Seeker: These, these guys are pretty nasty.
Kenzo: I, uh, cover any exposed skin that I've got with, uh...
Kenzo: Although I'm wearing a tunic and leggings and stuff, but yeah, my hands.
Seeker: Yeah, we're pretty... Our bodies are pretty covered probably, but yeah.
DM: Uh, so as you, um, as you continue then, it just, it seems like, uh,
DM: you know, this, this is,
DM: this is happening.
DM: This sort of like just the landscape itself is almost like rising up in this sort of bloodthirsty
DM: frenzy. Um,
DM: in the distance-
Seeker: Uh-
DM: Sorry, go ahead
Seeker: ...
Delwath: is there any... I was just gonna say, is there any...
Delwath: What I'm gonna... At some point I think it's worth taking a break and looking for, seeing if there's any signs of magic.
Kenzo: Yeah. I was just gonna say, and, and also if we should look for the tracks of, uh, that, if there are, if there are other human tracks around here.
Seeker: Yeah.
DM: Uh-
Unknown: Am I just sent you a message?
DM: Yep.
Unknown: At the gate.
DM: Uh, so you're still probably two, two miles away from the,
DM: from the towers at this point.
Kenzo: Oh, okay. Okay. I wanna do it when we get to the towers.
DM: A way, way back. Okay.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Um,
DM: any- anything anybody wants to do before, before you approach the towers?
Delwath: I mean, I'll just... Can we, can we look for any signs of human tracks?
DM: Sure.
Unknown: Yeah, exactly.
DM: Uh, make survival.
Unknown: Same.
Delwath: [laughs] Damn, what the fuck?
Unknown: Oh, shit.
Delwath: [laughs] Six, five, four, and three.
DM: There are no tracks.
DM: I mean, there's animal tracks.
DM: Um-
Seeker: Oh, my God.
Unknown: Hmm.
Seeker: I mean-
DM: But no, no tracks of, of, of, of humans or anything like that.
Seeker: Or like-
DM: You see a lot... I mean, it's clear that there's, uh,
DM: there's definitely a lot of tracks crossing here.
DM: Um-
Seeker: Mm
DM: ... it's just hard to pick out anything-
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Seeker: Right
DM: ... specific. Um,
DM: the... You know, so as you, so as you continue then, um, you see, uh,
DM: the t- the towers, as the towers are approaching, um,
DM: uh, a little bit to your, um,
DM: a little bit south of the trail, uh, you see, um,
DM: the
DM: dead corpse
DM: of w- of a giant scorpion nearly 10 feet long.
Seeker: Oh.
Unknown: 10 feet long.
DM: One claw ripped off, and, and near it a giant hyena,
DM: not dead, two dead around it, and it kind of limping, looks like very sick.
DM: Um, kind of like, uh,
DM: almost as if it's poisoned, just kind of partially paralyzed in a couple legs, snarling at you, but it can't move.
DM: It's like,
DM: uh, trying to charge at you and it, and it just, its, its back legs are paralyzed and it can't walk, but it's still, as it sees you, it looks up from sort of chewing on the, half-heartedly
DM: on the scorpion and
DM: s- sort of snarls, and foam and blood is, is around it, and it starts trying to drag itself, um, towards you,
DM: sort of yelping as it goes.
Kenzo: Uh, isn't this the plot of Princess Mononoke?
Seeker: [laughs] You're totally right.
Unknown: Yes.
Seeker: We just have to decapitate the forest god.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: And then we get immortality.
Seeker: That's how it works.
Seeker: But only when it's the Night Walker.
Seeker: I actually just recently watched that again.
Seeker: It's, that is a totally, totally amazing movie, but really intense.
Unknown: Yeah. Extremely intense.
Unknown: Um-
Delwath: Should we put this thing out of its misery?
Wellby: Well, uh, is there anything that it can tell us while it's alive?
Unknown: Uh, I mean,
Unknown: is there anything...
Wellby: Can we see anything about it?
Wellby: Um, is it possible to see if like there are magical traces on it right now while it's alive, or?
Kenzo: How far are we from, how far are we from the keep again, Tim?
DM: A mile and a half maybe.
Seeker: Eh. Hmm.
Seeker: What's the landscape around us like?
Unknown: Are we in this
Seeker: rocky desert kind of area again?
DM: Um,
DM: it's, it's kind of like behind Schwartz.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: Right. It's like
DM: maybe not quite so jagged, but it's, it is, it's like there's, you know, rocks and there's cracks in the land.
DM: There are like some plants and some like scrubby trees growing.
DM: Um, but it's definitely, it's, it's very different from the other side of the canyon.
DM: It's a complete change of scenery.
DM: It's, you know, these like cracks opening up before you, spiky rocks jutting out of the ground, almost like everything's been jumbled and scrambled.
DM: It makes no sense from a geological perspective.
DM: It's like,
DM: um-
Seeker: So there's a f- there's a topography known as karst caused by the delus- dissolution of soluble rock.
Seeker: It forms a kind of field of, of vertical limestone spikes.
DM: No, it's not that. It's not so ordered and regular as that.
DM: It's, it's almost as if like, uh, you know, you're, um- You know, somebody was playing with mud
DM: and dragged their fingers through the landscape, and it froze that way.
Unknown: Ominous.
Kenzo: I like his metaphor Tim keeps using about, like-
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: ... swords cutting through the land and fingers being dragged through the mud.
Unknown: Oh, man.
Unknown: It's almost like the Stone Titan.
Seeker: But I'm sort of, like, squinting around, even though there's a dying hyena foaming at the mouth, I'm looking at the rocks and, uh, trying to memorize it so that maybe I can make sketches later with the aim
Seeker: of imagining an aerial view of these giant furrows through the stone.
Unknown: Hm.
DM: So are you, are you doing anything with the hyena?
Delwath: Uh, I think we just...
Unknown: Just keep going.
Delwath: It seems wrong to just leave it howling for blood here.
Wellby: I will shoot it with an arrow to kill it.
Unknown: Sensible.
DM: Okay. It's easy to kill.
DM: I mean, it's badly wounded.
DM: Um, kind of slumps to the ground,
DM: uh, letting out a moan.
DM: And still, still, as you, as the arrow pierces it and it begins to die, it turns and it looks at you, the sort of viciousness in its eyes as, as
DM: consciousness fades.
Kenzo: What... Do we have an idea what, what, uh, hurt it?
Unknown: How it got hurt?
Delwath: Presumably the scorpion that's dead, right?
Unknown: It, it was poisoned, right?
Unknown: So...
DM: It s- it looked like it might have...
DM: It was probably poisoned.
Seeker: Uh, it's worth noting that those scorpions are probably very dangerous and all around this area.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: I don't like this at all.
Seeker: Some ancient hyenas and possibly lizards.
Unknown: Uh, we should-
Unknown: Onwards to the keep?
DM: We should keep a look-
Unknown: Yes.
Wellby: Yes.
Kenzo: We should... Does, does any, uh, uh...
Kenzo: Can we protect ourselves in any way?
Kenzo: Um, as we... This is, this is, this is, this is not feeling very good.
DM: Uh...
Unknown: Um...
Unknown: Protect yourselves, like-
DM: How? Exactly.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: Uh...
Wellby: Did you leave that extra chain mail back with the horse?
Delwath: Would anybody like some extra...
Delwath: Actually, no, I did leave it back with the horse.
Kenzo: All right. Let's, uh...
Unknown: What time of day is it now, Tim?
DM: Um,
DM: I mean, it took, took a while to get down the cliff carefully and across this la- It's slow going here.
DM: It's probably about lunchtime by the time-
Unknown: All right
DM: ... you know, you've gotten this far.
Kenzo: All right. Let's go check it out.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Let's go on.
DM: So,
DM: um-
Kenzo: Uh, Tim, as soon as I get in range, I do the thing.
DM: So the range of that is, is, is 30 feet, I believe.
DM: So, so let me g- There'll be an opportunity, but let me, you know, give you-
Unknown: Okay
DM: ... the approach description and stuff first.
DM: Um,
DM: so as you approach, um, you can see now, coming to these towers, that this is the, um, this is, uh, what little that stands
DM: of what used to be a large fort.
DM: So the towers, these two, like, gate towers rise above the landscape a little bit.
DM: Um, but they're set within, um, a ruined wall that, that stretches maybe, um,
DM: a rectangle maybe
DM: 100 feet, uh, on the short end-
Unknown: Mm
DM: ... and perhaps almost twice that on the long end.
DM: Um,
DM: set within, um,
DM: a sort of earthen works, uh, barrier, and a dike.
DM: It's clearly some sort of, uh, military fort.
DM: Um, on the outside of the fort, um,
DM: y- there's some, a small cluster of foundations and, and ruined buildings, um,
DM: on the outskirts of the road that, or the path, really.
DM: It's, it's no longer a clear road, that turns off the main trade road heading to the fort.
DM: Um, on either side of this, of this trade road, in between the sort of cluster of, of foundations and, um, the fort itself, still in the distance, you're still
DM: 100, 200 yards out, um, there's two large mounds.
DM: Um, one,
DM: as you're looking at the fort, on the left, a grassy mound with, uh,
DM: small, um,
DM: plants and a few small golden and white flowers blooming on it.
DM: On the left, a rocky mound, gravel, dirt.
DM: Um,
DM: from a distance, it's n- not easy to make out any more details than that.
DM: It's almost like two hills placed on the side, um, of, of this path.
DM: Uh, beyond the towers you see in the fort, a few buildings do seem to stand.
DM: Um, but you can't really construct, uh, details from this far away.
DM: Um,
DM: okay.
DM: Uh, so that's what you see.
DM: So think about what you guys wanna do.
DM: I have a message to send.
Delwath: I think we should investigate, right?
Unknown: Go in-
DM: Yeah
Unknown: ... is the idea.
Wellby: Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm.
DM: Um, hold on a sec.
Wellby: Building, expecting it's someone's home, probably.
DM: I, I mean, it's clearly in ruins, right?
DM: Um, so you just wanna...
DM: You're just, like, heading for the main gate.
DM: Um- Uh,
DM: and as you... W- uh, when do you wanna do your,
DM: your-
Kenzo: Do the thing? When we get to the gate.
DM: Okay. Hold on a sec.
DM: Um...
Kenzo: Or within range of the gate.
DM: Okay.
DM: [sighs]
DM: Um,
DM: okay. So, um,
DM: I'll, I'll get to that in a sec.
DM: Uh
Seeker: [gentle music] I should have typed
DM: these out in advance.
Seeker: It's all good, man. This is pretty, uh,
Unknown: it's pretty exciting.
Seeker: It's interesting. He didn't change the music, so that's good.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: I like this music. Whatever this music is, I like it.
DM: It, it'll change it as-
Seeker: I don't know what it is
DM: ... it'll change in a second.
Seeker: He's definitely not gonna change the music.
Wellby: Change to something even gentler and happier.
Seeker: [laughs] Right.
Seeker: [gentle music] I'm sure the horse is doing great.
Seeker: He's probably just had a snack, maybe-
DM: Yeah, the horse is-
Seeker: ... going for a nap right now
DM: ... or, or it just was a snack.
Seeker: [laughs]
Wellby: That horse was dead before we even got to the bottom of the cliff.
Seeker: [laughs] [keyboard clicking]
Unknown: Oh, I'm so stoked.
Seeker: I'm curious what you got up your sleeve there.
Seeker: [gentle music]
Unknown: Oh, [laughs] I like this music, too.
Unknown: [gentle music]
Unknown: Dude, monks are pretty sweet.
DM: Yep.
DM: Um...
DM: [gentle music] Sorry, guys.
DM: I should have really typed all this out in advance.
DM: I'm sending you each messages.
Unknown: Oh, geez.
Seeker: Cool, cool, cool.
Seeker: [gentle music]
Unknown: Awesome.
Seeker: The horse is alive. That's great to know.
Seeker: [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: You got a message from the horse.
Seeker: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: Just wanted to let you know I'm doing great.
Seeker: [laughs] [gentle music]
DM: Okay, so
DM: now...
Kenzo: Oh, I didn't realize I could throw darts.
Unknown: Damn.
DM: As you begin...
DM: [gentle music] Okay, should we end on a cliffhanger, or do you wanna keep going for another 30 minutes or so?
Seeker: I'm, I'm good to keep going.
Delwath: We can go for another... As long as it's really 30 minutes, that's okay.
Delwath: If it's an hour, I'm gonna fall asleep.
DM: No, I... It shouldn't be an hour.
DM: Um...
Kenzo: I'm definitely down for 30 more, if you guys are.
Seeker: Schwartz, you okay?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Sweet. Yes. Of course.
DM: As you approach...
Seeker: Oh, wait, we have to level up here, right?
Seeker: So-
DM: Yeah, yeah, go into D&D Beyond and, and just click the level up thing and do all the stuff you planned out.
DM: Um...
Seeker: But wait, where is it?
Delwath: If you click on your character sheet and say manage levels up on your main.
DM: Yeah, click on manage levels right below your name.
Seeker: Below my name.
Seeker: Oh, thank you.
DM: So,
DM: uh, oh, wait, I need to send a message, too.
DM: [gentle music]
Kenzo: Oh, so do we all get more hit points and stuff?
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: Yep.
Unknown: Do we have to roll that?
DM: No, it does that automatically.
Delwath: It should just do it automatically.
Unknown: Oh,
Unknown: okay.
DM: Ooh. [humming] Hmm.
Seeker: All right.
Seeker: I think I'm good.
DM: Let me know when you're, if you're, when you're all set.
Unknown: I'm good.
DM: Okay.
DM: [gentle music]
Unknown: Nice.
Unknown: Level two. [laughs]
DM: O- okay
Unknown: Oh, yes
DM: I sent... I, you got your...
DM: I also answered the question about-
Unknown: Oh
DM: ... your thing.
Unknown: Oh, geez.
Unknown: Um, as soon as I s-
DM: As you begin to... Sorry, go ahead.
Kenzo: Uh, yeah, so a- as we get closer to the gate, I just stop everybody.
Unknown: Um,
Kenzo: this is ominous, friends.
Kenzo: Something unnatural lies beyond,
Unknown: beyond. Something,
Kenzo: something dark and not living.
Seeker: Hmm.
Unknown: Hmm.
Seeker: That's worrisome.
Seeker: I'm, I'm interested-
Unknown: Have any of you-
Seeker: ... in, in the stone material of the towers.
Seeker: Can I use my stone cunning to do like try to understand the history of this place?
DM: So, um,
DM: yeah, you're, you're...
DM: So you're, you're sort of walking up to the gate, and you stop and say this as you begin passing the, the sort of...
DM: Kenzo stops and says this as you begin passing the, the sort of the two mounds on either side.
DM: So you, you go past the, the little cluster of foundations, and you begin to approach, um, the gate, the entryway itself, and Kenzo sort of grabs you as you're passing the,
DM: um,
DM: as you're passing the sort of rubble mound on the right.
Kenzo: Before we go any further, have, have any of you encountered anything like this before, something unnatural and undead?
Seeker: Undead?
Unknown: Hmm.
DM: And as you're looking around,
DM: um,
DM: you hear
DM: a...
DM: Uh, oh, hold on.
DM: Um...
DM: Um,
DM: okay, so as you're, as you're looking around, uh, and you know, you've grabbed everybody and you're stopped, you hear,
DM: like the sound of rocks, of, of rubble tumbling.
DM: And catching the corner of your eye is a bony arm reaching through the rubble pile, pulling
DM: it- grabbing and pulling itself out.
DM: And as the arm starts to pull on the, on the rubble, more rock shifts, and another one,
DM: this one holding a sword, starts to pull itself out.
DM: Where, where is this rubble pile?
DM: Several more of these. What?
Unknown: Are, are, are we on this map now?
Unknown: Should we put ourselves on the map?
DM: Oh, yeah. Uh, I-
Unknown: Oh, geez
DM: ... let's see.
Seeker: May- maybe it wants to be our friend. It's gonna be fine.
DM: So put yourself-
Unknown: You-
DM: Put yourselves wherever you
DM: wanna be.
Seeker: Oh, over there, huh?
Seeker: Actually, I'm, I'm going over to the, to the stone mound.
Seeker: I'm, I'm looking at it.
Kenzo: All right. Well, we'll all be, we'll all be near each other.
Kenzo: Each one of these squares represents how many feet?
DM: Five feet.
Seeker: Should we roll initiative?
DM: Uh, yes.
DM: I'll, I'll put these guys on the map in a second.
Seeker: Guys? Oh, geez.
Unknown: O- okay.
DM: So, so two start crawling out
DM: here.
Seeker: Oh, man.
DM: And two of them seem to be, um...
DM: Uh, let's see here.
DM: Uh, two of them are just completely...
DM: They're, um...
Seeker: [laughs]
DM: So two of them that are, that are sort of crawling out, um, are just like bony skeletons.
DM: There's no flesh. There's nothing.
DM: They have no, no weapons, no armor, just their bare fists as they crawl out and start looking towards you.
DM: Um, two of them have, have swords, rusting but still seemingly sharp, as they begin to pull their way out of this rubble.
DM: And you can see as you stop and look here that, um,
DM: this was made easier by the fact that someone or something or some creature seems to have been digging in this rubble at some point or another.
DM: And there's, there's been some, uh, dirt that's been cleared, and some of the stone has been shifted, um, at, at some point making a path where these things could emerge
DM: from.
DM: And now, yes, let's roll initiative.
DM: Um, yeah.
Unknown: Come on.
Wellby: Uh, do you have, do I have it here?
Kenzo: Uh, I'm clicking the initiative button.
Wellby: Six.
DM: Why is it not rolling?
DM: Do you guys all roll initiative?
Delwath: Yeah.
Unknown: I did.
DM: Yes, Seeker is 18.
DM: Oh, there it is. Okay, sorry.
DM: Ah, fuck. That's fine.
DM: And, um, is 19.
DM: Okay, so
DM: Wellby, you're first.
Wellby: I, I, uh, hmm.
Wellby: Can I hide in this terrain at all?
DM: [laughs]
Wellby: It's a really big open area.
DM: Um,
DM: on the... I mean, you could hide on the far side of this rubble pile over here.
Wellby: Mm-hmm.
DM: Uh, there's not...
DM: This is pretty open terrain.
DM: You could hide behind, if you could get all the way behind the wall, this rubble wall, you could hide there.
DM: Um, there is not, not shown on the map, but like in front of the wall, the,
DM: the two, the 10 feet in front of the wall is a bit of a ditch.
DM: So you could probably hide in the ditch.
Wellby: Mm.
DM: There's like a causeway that runs across the ditch, but like all of, all of this up here-
Wellby: Yeah
DM: ... the 10 feet in front of the wall is a ditch.
Wellby: All right. Well, I'm gonna move this way.
Wellby: One, two, three, four, five with my normal action, and I'm gonna shoot this guy.
Wellby: I don't know if you can see.
Wellby: I'm gonna shoot something.
DM: This one?
Wellby: Yes.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Shoot the one with the sword.
DM: Shoot the one with the sword? So this one and this one have swords.
Delwath: Oh.
Wellby: And the other is just no sword?
DM: This one and this one have no swords.
DM: They're just normal.
Wellby: Yeah, I'll shoot the, I'll shoot the sword.
DM: This one?
Wellby: Sword guy. Yep.
DM: Okay. That, uh, misses.
Delwath: Yikes.
Wellby: Bummer. All right. I will, um,
Wellby: use my cunning action to, uh, get back a little bit further.
DM: Okay.
DM: Uh, okay.
DM: So this one is like,
DM: like looking around, like
DM: just, uh,
DM: crawling out of the earth, like arms, bones just running out, and it's just gonna charge for the closest living thing it sees-
Delwath: Oh, man
DM: ... which is Seeker,
DM: and it will, um,
DM: punch you with its fist,
DM: which is... What's your AC?
Delwath: Uh, 13.
DM: Okay. It misses as you duck out of the way.
Delwath: Whew.
DM: This skeleton now runs forward, one, two, again, just heading for the closest living thing it can see,
DM: um, and is going to
DM: swing its rusting sword at Delwath, missing.
DM: Delwath, you're up.
Delwath: All right. Um,
Delwath: I will just attack,
Delwath: um... So I will attack, let's see, um,
Delwath: um, I'll mutter, I'll, um, I'll mutter, uh...
Delwath: This is the guy with the sword?
DM: Yep, the one in front of you has a sword.
Delwath: Right. Um,
Delwath: so let's see.
Delwath: One second. Let me just...
Delwath: Um, I'll step
Delwath: sort of...
Delwath: Well, no, this is fine.
Delwath: Um, I will curse this using my hexblade's curse.
Delwath: I mutter... You hear Del- Delwath sort of mutter something in Elvish, like a, an, an incantation of some kind,
Delwath: and then swing his longbow, or his long sword.
DM: That hits.
Delwath: Nice.
Delwath: Um, and it takes plus two extra damage.
DM: So
DM: eight?
Delwath: Eight, yep.
Kenzo: Why does it take plus two? Oh, because of the spell or the-
Delwath: Yeah, 'cause he, he muttered something in El- Delwath muttered something in Elvish and then just swung his sword, um-
DM: Mm-hmm
Delwath: ... at the creature.
DM: So as you, as you, uh, smash into it your, um...
DM: Yeah, okay. Um, there's, there's like a crack as, as it, as it looks pretty wounded by that blow.
Delwath: Nice.
DM: Okay. Now this one is going to run forward again at you,
DM: and it is going to
DM: hit you.
Delwath: Hold on.
DM: Well...
DM: Yep?
Delwath: Uh, I'm gonna cast shield.
DM: What does that make your AC?
Delwath: Uh, 20.
DM: It misses then.
Delwath: So you see Delwath flings up his arm as the creature comes nearby, and like a shimmering, um, like wall of force appears in between,
Delwath: um, him-
Wellby: Ooh
Delwath: ... and the creature that's attacking.
Wellby: Nice.
DM: Okay, this one is gonna run.
DM: Let's see. Seeker is closer, so run there.
Delwath: Shit. Shit. Ah, that's not what I need, Seeker.
DM: Uh, coming at you with his short sword, which hits.
Delwath: Ugh.
DM: Doing four points of, of piercing damage as his, this rusting sword just like cuts-
Delwath: Oh, rusty swords
DM: ... into your side.
Delwath: Rusty swords.
DM: Missed you.
Delwath: Um...
DM: Oh, I somehow missed you on the initiative order.
DM: Sorry about that Okay, Kenzo, you're up, then Seeker
Unknown: Okay. Kenzo, um,
Kenzo: rushes over to Seeker's side and you see Kenzo, um, kinda take his quarterstaff and then start just...
Kenzo: His, his hands start moving incredibly quickly, you know, kind of signing in front of his face, and then, um, takes the staff, whips it forward in a flur- in a furious motion,
Kenzo: and, um, smashes down on the skeleton with the, um,
Unknown: with the sword.
Unknown: And...
DM: That hits.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: So five damage.
Unknown: And then-
DM: Um, uh-
Unknown: Oh, go ahead.
DM: Hold on.
DM: So as you, as you smash down on it with your quarterstaff, you just hear this, like, cracking noise as, like, all of the bones in its
DM: arm just, like, start to shatter, and it seems, like, quite badly wounded by this strike.
Unknown: Mm.
Seeker: Okay.
Kenzo: Okay. And then, um, I take, again, another, another, uh...
Kenzo: With my hands, smashing forward with the staff and then swiping with my, my right arm.
Unknown: And?
Unknown: Nice.
DM: That hits.
DM: Um, and with your, with your fist just flying f- fast, you just punch straight into its, into its ribcage, and all of the bones,
DM: uh, in its entire, like, ribcage area, including its spine, just shatter at once, and it collapses in upon itself, um, falling into
DM: a pile on the ground.
Kenzo: Perfect. And then, Tim, um, as I am continuing in my flurry based on the, the s- the small little ritual you saw me do at the start-
DM: Yep
Kenzo: ... I continue to attack in a, in a, in a flurry of moves, and, and, uh, Seeker, I, I sort of, you know, step right to your side, and then, uh, in another flurry of blows,
Kenzo: strike the, the skeleton that's directly next to you.
Unknown: And...
DM: Um, that unfortunately misses.
Kenzo: But still continuing in my flurry of blows [laughs]
Seeker: [laughs]
DM: You only get three.
Delwath: If I, again... Huh?
DM: You only get three attacks with flurry of blows.
Kenzo: I thought I get two. I thought I get two extra ones if I do, uh, uh-
DM: Oh, it's, it's one... It gives you one extra.
Unknown: Ah, one extra.
DM: You can make two attacks as a bonus attack, and one attack as a normal attack.
Unknown: Ah, okay. All right. Okay.
DM: So three total.
Unknown: Got it. Now I get it.
DM: And remember to mark off a, a ki point.
Unknown: Yep.
DM: Okay. So Seeker?
Seeker: Um,
Seeker: I, uh, begin weaving a, a dreamy, uh,
Seeker: uh, a net, I believe.
Seeker: Just watching me draw this with my fingertips in the air makes you feel sleepy.
Seeker: And I, uh, fling it outward,
Seeker: uh, in such a pl- position so that the net will touch many of the skeletons as possible,
Seeker: um, which is to say within a 20 feet...
Seeker: Creatures within 20 feet.
Seeker: Okay, let's see.
Seeker: So is there a t- a point where I can get all of them?
Delwath: Right, right, right there.
DM: Oh, that's your-
Unknown: Oh, no, right...
Seeker: Hmm.
Seeker: What is this? See-
DM: If you're casting what I think you are, you might wanna read the spell description
Seeker: ... Oh, no.
DM: Before you do it
Seeker: ... I'm always making mistakes with spells.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: Is it sleep?
Seeker: Yeah.
Delwath: Does it not affect undead?
Seeker: Oh, God, you're right.
Seeker: I missed that. It's right at the end of the description.
Seeker: Uh, I'm gonna cast, uh...
Seeker: Oh, God. Uh,
Seeker: what can I do here?
Seeker: Well,
Seeker: I'm gonna, um, quickly sketch a crude picture of a skeleton, uh, exploding into pieces and, and stick it onto Kenzo's forehead w-
Seeker: and it begins to glow like before, thinking, "Huh, that worked really well last time."
Seeker: Um, that's the, uh, runic inspiration.
Seeker: Um,
Seeker: but I'm gonna run...
Seeker: Uh, where can I go?
Seeker: Basically
Seeker: here.
Seeker: Does that make sense?
Seeker: I guess I could go here.
Seeker: No.
Delwath: But don't get in the middle of all of them, right?
Seeker: No, no, no.
Unknown: What you get, you know-
DM: If, if you go, if you move out of combat of this one, it'll get an attack of opportunity on you
Seeker: ... Yeah. So I wanna go actually here and Thunder Wave.
DM: Okay. So that's, we decided that's nine squares around you, right?
Seeker: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Okay. So it needs to make a constitution saving throw.
Seeker: So once again, I draw a giant glowing arrow pointing at the ground, thrust it downwards.
DM: Uh, okay. It makes its save, so it takes half damage, I believe.
Seeker: Uh,
Seeker: on a failed sa-
Seeker: Half is 1 D8. So it's not pushed.
DM: So you just keep the damage you rolled and you divide it by two, so it's three damage instead of, um-
Seeker: Okay
DM: ... seven, and I think it's not pushed.
DM: Is that right? If it makes its save.
Seeker: True. That's true.
Unknown: Correct.
Seeker: It is.
DM: Okay. So as you slam down, it, it rattles this, this creature, but not, um, it's not quite so dramatic as the effect it had on the lizard, uh,
DM: two nights ago.
Seeker: Mm.
DM: And it, the, the skeleton itself seems shaken but not, but not moved.
DM: Um, that brings us to Alton.
Unknown: Wellby
Wellby: Wellby
DM: Sorry, Wellby.
DM: I gotta fix that. It's
Wellby: Moving forward, uh, and that was good.
Wellby: But if we go over here, there's another arrow.
Unknown: Sch- Schwartz, it's a little hard to hear you.
Seeker: Tim, can you turn up the music a little bit?
DM: Yep, I just did. Uh, which one?
DM: This one here?
Wellby: Yes.
DM: Okay, so you do get sneak attack 'cause Kenzo's in melee with, or Delwath's-
Unknown: Oh
DM: ... in melee with it.
DM: So, um,
DM: so as you launch your arrow, um, it, uh,
DM: it flies true and you manage to strike, um, straight at its skull with your...
DM: as it's distracted by the, the black flowing shield around, around Delwath.
DM: And, um, with the force of your arrow,
DM: its skull shatters,
DM: and it also collapses into a pile of bones.
Unknown: Mm.
Wellby: Yay. [laughs]
DM: Okay, so Seeker, you're back up again, 'cause I did your turn out of order last time.
Unknown: Oh, okay.
Unknown: Uh, oh, man.
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: Um,
Seeker: oh, did I not press the cast button before?
Unknown: I did.
DM: You did.
Seeker: But it didn't use up a spell slot for some reason.
DM: So you probably have to refresh in order f- to see it, I think.
Unknown: Oh, like reload the page?
Wellby: Mm-hmm.
DM: Oh, no, it doesn't seem like it did.
DM: I don't know. Just mark one...
DM: You can just mark one off.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: That's fine.
Unknown: Um,
Seeker: what else can I even do, though?
Unknown: Oh, geez.
Seeker: Um, well, I will, um,
Seeker: draw another, uh, picture of an exploding skeleton in the air and f- fling it in the direction of Delwath, and it sticks to his forehead and
Seeker: glows there, inspiring him.
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: and I will
Unknown: maybe just kind of run away.
Seeker: I can run five squares?
DM: Yeah, you can use your action to disengage and run.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So you don't get an opportunity attack, and you can run to, like, here, basically.
Unknown: Yeah, I'll do that.
Delwath: Um, did you kill the one that I was attacking, or did you attack the other one?
Seeker: Wellby killed it.
Delwath: Yeah, Wellby killed the one I was attacking.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Yes, he had killed the one you were attacking.
Unknown: Took the one with the sword.
Unknown: Okay, so I'm done.
DM: Yep. Okay, so, okay, this one now is gonna swing at Kenzo.
DM: Um, the two ones with swords now are dead, it's just these, these ones with their fists.
DM: Uh, so that's gonna hit, um, and it does one point of damage to
DM: Kenzo.
Unknown: All right. I, I'll live.
DM: 'Cause it just punches with not nearly the force of your punch.
DM: Delwath, you're up.
Unknown: Um, I'll just attack it.
DM: That hits.
DM: Um...
Delwath: No extra damage, 'cause the cur- the one I cursed died.
DM: Okay, so but nine points is still enough to, um, to knock this one
DM: to, to pieces.
DM: And now that you sort of got your feet under you, these seem to be dying relatively quickly.
DM: Um, Kenzo, you're up.
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: Smash down at it with my staff.
Unknown: Uh,
Unknown: and...
DM: Um, that hits. And again, the force of your staff as you
DM: swing it around your head and just slam it into the skeleton, you can hear, like, bones cracking loudly, um, as it, as your staff connects.
DM: And you can still make one unarmed strike without spending any ki.
Kenzo: And I do, whirling back around with bare fists,
Unknown: and...
DM: That hits again, and your, and your fist is just...
DM: The strength of your fist just, again, shatters, um, its ribcage as you just slam your palm into his bones.
DM: And it seems, seems very brittle.
DM: Every time you're hitting it and whacking it with your staff and your flying fist, the bones are just breaking around you in this sort of flurry.
DM: Now there's two piles of
DM: skeletons partially turned to dust
DM: floating, you know, lying on the ground by your side, um, as you all look at each other,
DM: hoping no more are climbing out of this part, this now apparently partially excavated, um,
DM: mound of
DM: rock and dirt.
Kenzo: Right after I, uh, smash the last one in the ribcage and it crumbles to dust, and then I look at all of us, and then I...
Kenzo: You know, the, the kind of piles of dead bones.
Kenzo: And I look at you guys, I'm like, "We're getting pretty good at killing these things."
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: [laughs] Oh, man, I hope no more come out of there, though.
Seeker: Geez.
Kenzo: I've never fought skeletons before, I can say that much.
Wellby: Mm-mm.
Seeker: What is this place?
Unknown: I don't like this place at all.
Seeker: Can I investigate-
Unknown: Do you want, like-
Seeker: ... this stone mound?
DM: Yeah. Uh, make, um,
DM: I guess I'm gonna say investigation check.
Seeker: Uh, okay.
Seeker: That's not very good.
DM: You don't see much.
DM: I mean, it's, something's cl- it's been...
DM: You know, as you sort of walk around the sides of it, you can see that something's been
DM: dug out. Um,
DM: clearly there's some, uh- It's been disturbed in, in some way, but you have no real clue
DM: how or why or when or by what.
DM: Um-
Kenzo: That, can we, can we all investigate it?
Delwath: Yeah, I'll go investigate as well.
DM: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: Same.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Investigation.
Seeker: I'm also more interested in the longer, uh, historical
Seeker: question.
DM: Uh, yes. Um,
DM: so, so not really seeing much, uh,
DM: that you can comment on, uh, on the mound itself, you, um, drift over and kind of start examining the walls and the, and the fort.
Seeker: Yeah.
DM: So there's like this outer wall, and then there's some towers beyond.
DM: So make a history check for that.
Seeker: And then with stone cunning...
Seeker: Doo, doo, doo, history related to origin of stonework.
Seeker: You're proficient.
DM: Yes.
Seeker: And double your proficiency bonus to the check then.
DM: So, so-
Seeker: So history is plus four, so it's plus eight?
DM: No, it's an additional plus two.
DM: So roll a normal history check and then add two.
DM: So 14.
Seeker: Yeah.
DM: Okay. So let's see.
DM: Delwath's, Delwath's investigating the s- the stone.
Unknown: Yes.
DM: Wellby and Kenzo, what are you guys doing?
Unknown: Uh, let's see.
Kenzo: What am I doing? What would be good to investigate?
Kenzo: I will, I will do a history check on this place in general.
Seeker: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: Can I do that?
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: And, and Wellby?
Delwath: [laughs] I do not know any history about this place.
DM: Wellby, uh, what do you wanna do?
Wellby: Uh,
Wellby: I don't... Uh,
Wellby: [laughs] I'm sort of at a loss.
Wellby: I'm, I'm thrown for a loop a little bit by, by these, uh, these undead creatures.
Wellby: Um,
Wellby: I think I'm just gonna stay alert and keep an eye out for anything else that's moving.
Wellby: Um, and can I see anything,
Wellby: anything else?
DM: Okay. Uh, so give me a perception check.
Wellby: Hmm.
DM: Uh, okay. Hold on.
DM: Um...
Seeker: Hmm.
DM: Uh, okay. So who else?
DM: Let's see. Um,
DM: so, so Delwath, you're poking around the, the stone some more?
Unknown: Yes.
DM: Right? Okay.
Unknown: Hmm.
Delwath: So Delwath will say the, this seems, um,
Unknown: seems like it was dug up
Unknown: some time ago.
Unknown: A week, maybe.
Seeker: Hmm.
Unknown: A little longer.
DM: Hmm.
Delwath: But not, you know, years.
Delwath: Would this prot- perhaps align with the traveler?
DM: Potentially. It could.
Seeker: Hmm.
Kenzo: I think we're getting closer and closer to the source of this-
Unknown: Yeah
Seeker: ... well, this, this mania.
Seeker: As far as the fort itself, it has all the markings of the, uh, Dunmari style of, uh, defensive fort construction, uh, of the era of the Great War.
Seeker: Uh-
Unknown: Hmm
Seeker: ... from what I've read,
Seeker: a number of similar forts to this one were built in the, in the northern part of Dunmar, uh, as defense against, uh, creatures coming out of the mountains.
Seeker: Uh, mostly hobgoblins.
Unknown: Hmm. How far are the mountains from here?
DM: Uh, I mean, you're probably
DM: less than a week's travel.
DM: Um-
Kenzo: By the way, Tim, I feel like, uh, at the beginning of each session, we should do, like, Game of Thrones, and you should pull out a map.
Unknown: Like, we should do a map of the regions-
DM: Yeah. Okay
Kenzo: ... just so we can, like... You know, you know, seriously, so you can be like-
Seeker: I like that. I like that
Unknown: ... this is where we are.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: This is where the town was.
Kenzo: This is the ca- you know, so we can kinda see, like, where we've been traveling, you know?
Seeker: A review, yeah.
Unknown: You, you should, like, share screen.
Wellby: Yeah, that would be cool.
Kenzo: And then give us a little, you know, little dash, dashed, uh, little journey line.
Seeker: A little fly in, yeah.
Unknown: That would be really cool.
Kenzo: In addition to all of the amazing, als- all the other incredible, amazing, your work you're doing, you're doing that way.
DM: Yeah, I'll just add animating a map onto my list [laughs] of to dos.
Kenzo: [laughs] In Minecraft, please. Like, I, you know.
Seeker: Right. Yeah, yeah. [laughs]
DM: [laughs] I just sent you a message, Schwartz, and I think everybody else got theirs.
DM: Okay, so.
Seeker: Did I get a message?
DM: No, 'cause you rolled a four, dude.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: You don't, you don't remember anything.
Seeker: Oh, no.
Wellby: I'll say to Delwath, yeah, that timing lines up.
Wellby: I think someone's been here in the last few weeks.
Wellby: The digging-
Wellby: The camp that they tried to hide, it fits
Kenzo: One person? More than one? Is it a group?
Wellby: Just one. Just one there and just one here as far as I can tell.
Unknown: Probably the same?
DM: The... Yeah, so the...
DM: What did you roll?
DM: 17. Yeah, so the... I mean, there are definitely not, not tracks.
DM: I mean, it's been... It seems like there's not a lot of like, you know, obvious tracks, but
DM: the area s- almost seems like it's been lived in a little, especially sort of over towards the, um,
DM: you know, like someone was traveling in between these foundations and ruins over here and the, um, and the mound, and like there's a bit of a, a bit of a sort
DM: of traveled path and like every...
DM: And you see, like, you know, when you're paying attention, like, bits of, you know, a, a broken bit of a pick or something like that, sort of like signs of excavation.
Delwath: Is this, is the, is the mound, like, dug up to the bottom?
Delwath: Like, can we continue the excavation and see what's in here?
Seeker: Oh, yeah, nice idea.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: I mean, I'm not saying-
DM: It's already tried
Unknown: ... I'm not saying we should.
Unknown: I'm just, like, is there-
Unknown: Uh...
DM: It's, it was not, it's not completely excavated.
DM: That's certain.
DM: Um.
Unknown: Where did these skeletons come from?
Kenzo: Does it r- require somebody to animate them?
Kenzo: Do they... Does... I, I know nothing of these beasts.
Kenzo: Actually, Tim, can I do, like, an arcana check?
DM: I would say for skeletons, I'd say religion.
Unknown: Religion?
Unknown: What?
Kenzo: Aha. I'll do a religion check.
DM: Whoop. Um.
Kenzo: You can just say it out loud, and I'll-
DM: Yeah, so
Unknown: ... read it.
DM: So you would, I mean,
DM: th-
DM: s- you know, undead in general would be, you know, perceived as or, or considered sort of an affront to the natural order of things, and
DM: s- you know, something magical would have to animate them.
DM: There's many ways that un- that undead can be animated.
DM: It can be, you know, necromantic magic.
DM: It can be their soul is cursed.
DM: It can be, you know-
Unknown: Mm-hmm
DM: ... um,
DM: some divine being,
DM: you know, curses them and refuses to accept their, their soul upon their death.
DM: It can be, um-
Kenzo: But, but do I... You know, if there are four of them crawling out of a mound together, like, you know, does that, that feel a little bit more like probably somebody was involved in raising them or something?
DM: It's-
Unknown: Hard to say?
DM: It's hard to say, I would say.
Unknown: Yeah, I don't know. I-
DM: I mean, you don't...
DM: Y- you could, like, examine the skeletons in more detail, I guess.
DM: Um.
Unknown: Sure. Why not?
Seeker: I'm curious about the grassy mound also to see if I can find anything about that.
DM: Yeah, it's probably a grave.
DM: It just hasn't been dug up.
DM: Yeah, the grassy mound-
Unknown: Oh
Seeker: ... has not been excavated.
Seeker: But maybe this other one looked like that before.
Seeker: I did not gather that.
DM: It could have, right?
DM: It's, it's certainly, it's clearly been disturbed.
DM: W- whether it was, you know, a grassy mound before and somebody just didn't finish excavating it seems certainly plausible.
DM: Um,
DM: uh, g- give me an investigation check for looking at the bodies.
Unknown: Yeah. Ah.
DM: Um,
DM: so these are not...
DM: They look humanoid, but they're not human skeletons.
Unknown: Hmm. Huh.
DM: Not entirely sure, sure what.
DM: It's obviously something similar to human, but the, the
DM: skulls are a little too thick and sort of s- um, compressed, and the bones are a little too big, and the proportions are just off a little bit.
Unknown: Could they be-
DM: It seems like-
Unknown: ... hobgoblins?
DM: They could be. That would be plausible.
Unknown: Hmm. Hmm.
Unknown: Hmm.
Seeker: And we're outside the fortification here?
DM: Currently you're outside the fortification.
Unknown: Hmm.
Unknown: Do these look like,
Unknown: like, um,
Delwath: mass graves after a battle?
DM: S-
DM: um,
DM: yeah, that would be plausible.
Delwath: Right, like i- could this be where the dead were buried after a hobgoblin attack on the fort kind of thing?
DM: It-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... that could be, for sure.
Unknown: Wouldn't they have burned the bodies, though?
Kenzo: Why bury them unless they were
Unknown: denizens or friends?
Wellby: I mean, could be short on wood in this landscape.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Hmm.
Seeker: Or maybe the hobgoblins won the battle.
Unknown: Hmm. Also true.
Unknown: Hmm.
Delwath: Do hobgoblins bury their dead?
Unknown: What's the usual...
DM: Um,
DM: uh, yeah, you, you would know.
DM: You've... I mean, they would typically burn their dead.
Unknown: Hmm.
Delwath: I mean, it would be unusual for...
Delwath: I guess I don't know that much about human battle cultures, but, like, would it be unusual for-
DM: It, it would be unusual for hobgoblins to dig graves and bury their dead, for sure.
DM: I-
Unknown: But I mean, would it be-
DM: Generally speaking, in, in your experience, hobgoblins, if they do anything besides loot their dead, would, would burn them.
Delwath: Would it be unusual for h- humans to bury hobgoblins?
DM: Uh, you don't have a good sense of that.
DM: It would certainly be unusual for elves to bury hobgoblins.
Kenzo: So Tim, going back to my, uh, religion check for which I rolled a 16, uh-
DM: Uh, yeah
Kenzo: ... it, like, if these skeletons kind of just crawled up now, like,
Kenzo: you know, would it be the case that- If they, you know, if they're animated now, you know, us, us appearing, would it be reasonable that whatever animated them was like a recent
Kenzo: phenomenon as opposed to they were like stuck in the ground for like 100 years and then they, we showed up and then they animated because of our presence?
Kenzo: You know, you know, it's like, like can the magic persist over long periods of time or is the fact that they just popped up now likely that whatever animated them was recent?
DM: They don't need to eat or sleep.
DM: Once they're animated, they could just be stuck underground for 100 years.
Seeker: Ah, okay. All right.
DM: And something could have dug them up, or they could be recent.
DM: It's hard. You can't really tell because-
Unknown: Okay. Okay. Got it.
Kenzo: But there, there's plausible explanations for both.
Kenzo: Like it could have been there for a long time or could be recent.
DM: Right. It's clearly been recently disturbed, so if that's connected-
Unknown: Right, right
DM: ... that suggests a recent.
DM: But you don't really know if that's connected or if that just freed something that was trapped underground.
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: Yeah, so maybe digging up that other mound is not gonna be a good idea.
Kenzo: [laughs] If there are other, uh, animated undead things down there.
Seeker: I mean, I can use my
Seeker: sense of stone to see if there's any valuable minerals inside these mounds, but I don't know if that's worth doing even.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Hmm.
Seeker: Hmm. Versus like should we just like go into the fort and see what's in there?
Unknown: Right.
Wellby: I think we should move on. I think we should move in.
DM: Okay. Anything else you wanna do?
DM: Okay. So...
Seeker: Um.
DM: Sorry, go ahead.
Seeker: No, you go ahead, Tim.
DM: I mean, this is where we're gonna end, so if there's anything you wanna do outside the fort, let's wrap that up and then we'll end as you enter the fort.
Seeker: Okay.
Wellby: Well, I'm just remembering that in high school I had a 1:00 AM curfew that I had to be home by.
Seeker: [laughs]
Wellby: So I feel like this is probably the right time to stop.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: It is. It is. What time is it where you are, Schwartz?
Wellby: 11:30.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Okay. So
DM: dusting yourselves off from the battle,
DM: you, uh,
DM: head up the causeway
DM: towards the towers.
DM: As you begin to approach the towers, you see in front of you, um, the inside of the fort, uh, beyond the sort of earthen dike.
DM: And you can see that there are a few buildings that remain standing.
DM: Straight ahead of you, there's a large sort of central headquarters building.
DM: The roof is of course collapsed or burnt or destroyed somehow.
DM: But most of the walls remain intact, intact.
DM: And to the, to your right, sort of between you and the, um, and the headquarters but off to the right a little bit, there's a pentagonal building.
DM: Um, seems to be in surprisingly good repair.
DM: Um, a metal domed roof still standing, walls, um, seemingly undestroyed or unharmed, or at least not nearly
DM: as badly harmed as the rest of the buildings.
DM: Looking around, the, other than that, everything else is just ruins.
DM: There's like clearly, um, stone sort of laid around like, like marking foundations and things of a number of long buildings, probably barracks or stables.
DM: But other than those two, um, everything else is collapsed.
DM: Looking across this expanse,
DM: thinking about what to do next
DM: is where we're gonna stop.
Unknown: All right.
DM: And we'll pick up next time.
Unknown: Super fun.
DM: Awesome.
Unknown: I gotta go to sleep though.
Seeker: Yeah, that was a good one, Tim. Thank you.